翻译修订&时间轴｜goodliuwu
字幕转制｜天外生物
感谢原字幕制作者
一、二、三
One, two, three.
雷德利·斯科特 电影
火柴人
[火柴人：美国俚语，指高级骗子让你心甘情愿出大价钱买他的火柴]
一、二、三
One, two, three.
- 恭喜你  - 什么？
- Well, congratulations.  - Excuse me?
- 你妥妥的是三项精彩大奖之一的中奖者  - 什么？
- You're a guaranteed winner of one of three fabulous prizes.  - What?
- 你以前中过大奖吗？ - 没，从来没有
- Have you won anything major before?  - No, never.
- 那么你现在中了  - 哦，天啊
- Well, you have now.  - Oh, my God.
- 你是在开玩笑吗？ - 不是，已经确认了
- Are you kidding?  - No, it's confirmed.
你确定吗？好啊，我赢了什么？
Are you sure? Okay, what did I win?
要么是雪佛兰开拓者，或是巴黎
Either the Chevy Blazer, the Paris...
- 你家有滤水器吗？ - 水龙头过滤器？不，先生，我没有
- Do you have a water filtration system?  - A faucet filter? No, sir. I don 't.
- 你看报纸或者看电视吗？ - 有时候会
- Do you read the papers or watch TV?  - Sometimes, yeah.
那你就应该看过我们公司的广告
Well, then you've probably seen our advertisements.
正如我说过的，埃里克，政府会要你为奖品交税
As I said Erik, the government is gonna make you pay a tax on the prize.
但如果你购买华特生两千型滤水器
But if you buy the Waterson 2000 water filtration system...
奖品就可以申报成销售支出，那你就不用交税
...the prize gets recorded as a sales expense, and you don't pay any tax.
- 很划算，对吗？ - 没错
- Good deal, huh?  - Yeah.
- 没错  - 然后我还能得到巴黎旅游？
- Yeah.  - And then I get the trip to Paris?
你一定会得到三项大奖之一
You're guaranteed one of those three prizes.
我要一个快递到你家去，你给他一张支票
I'm gonna have a courier come to your house. You're gonna give him a check.
他回到我这里，我们会决定你获得哪一个奖品
He's gonna come to me and we'll decide which one of those prizes you get.
明白这个流程吗？
See how that works?
- 我得付多少钱？ - 相当于三百九十八美元
- How much do I pay?  - Three hundred ninety-eight dollars even.
- 你在商店买得花两倍价钱  - 我需要和我丈夫说说
- You'd pay twice that in stores.  - I need to speak to my husband.
知道吗，艾琳？我的主管刚走进我办公室，他极愿意和你聊聊
You know what, Irene? My supervisor just stepped into my office, and he would love to talk to you.
你能稍等一下吗？谢了，艾琳
Can you hold just a sec? Thanks, Irene.
- 早安  - 是哪一位？
- Good morning.  - Who says so?
艾琳·费斯克，她想先跟她丈夫谈一下
Irene Fisk. She wants to talk to her husband first.
费斯克太太，约翰·古休，地区副总裁
Mrs. Fisk, John Goodhew, regional vice president.
恭喜，你希望要哪一个奖品？
Congratulations. Which prize are you hoping for?
- 哦，巴黎  - 要是我也会选这个
- Oh, Paris.  - That would be my choice too.
我们从来没去过
We've never been.
[5个孙子]
我们从来没去过
We've never been.
[5个孙子]
我的同事告诉我说你有五个孙子？哇
My associate tells me you have five grandkids? Wow.
我理解这事你想先和丈夫商量一下
I understand you'd like to speak to your husband first about this.
我理解原因
I can understand why.
但事情是这样的，艾琳，我的秘书今天下午生小孩了
But the thing is, Irene, my secretary is having a baby this afternoon.
这办公室里所有人都要赶到医院去
Everyone at the office is about to head to the hospital.
那真是太好了
Well, that's wonderful.
所以，我确认下你的地址，我就能交给我们的快递服务
Now, let me confirm your address so I can get it to our courier service.
好吧
All right.
嘿
Hey
抱歉抱歉
Sorry, sorry.
午饭有何想法？
Any thoughts on lunch?
香辣墨鱼？
Spicy calamari?
泰国菜？
Thai food?
俾格米土著
Pygmies.
欧提斯，嘘，嘘
Otis, hush, hush.
有什么事吗？
Can I help you?
- 卡洛琳·谢弗？ - 对
- Carolyn Schaffer?  - Yes?
我是凯威探员，这是柯尔探员，我们是联邦交易委员会的
I'm Agent Kellaway. This is Agent Cole. We're from the Federal Trade Commission.
很抱歉打扰你，可以的话，我们想问你几个问题
Sorry to disturb you. We'd like to ask you a few questions if we could.
- 没出什么事吧？ - 我们希望如此，夫人
- Is everything all right?  - We hope so, ma'am
谢弗太太，你能不能告诉我们那个人在电话里的确切说辞？
Mrs. Schaffer, can you tell us exactly what the man said on the phone?
他说有个比赛活动，而我赢得了奖品
He said that there'd been a contest, and I had won a prize.
说下星期会举行摸彩，而我会赢得
There'd be a drawing next week, and I'd win...
要么是雪佛兰开拓者，或是钻石项链
...either a Chevy Blazer, a diamond necklace...
或者游意大利还是法国，我不记得了
...or a trip to Italy or France. I don't remember.
还说只要我买一个他们的滤水器，我就可以不用缴税
And that if I bought one of their filtration things, I wouldn't have to pay the tax.
- 老天，卡洛琳  - 我想给你个惊喜
- Jesus, Carolyn.  - I wanted to surprise you.
我很遗憾告诉你，夫人，你什么奖品都不会拿到
I'm sorry to tell you this, ma'am, but you won't be receiving any prize.
而且我很遗憾地告诉你是欺诈受害者
And I'm sorry to tell you that you've been the victim of fraud.
欧提斯，不要吵了
Otis, knock it off.
这不是世上最新的诈欺行为
It's not the newest swindle in the world.
他们先拿假东西引诱你，然后再卖给你不值钱的东西
They bait you with something bogus, then sell you something worthless.
你给他们多少钱，谢弗太太？
How much did you give them, Mrs. Schaffer?
七百美元
Seven hundred dollars.
- 这值多少？ - 任何五金店里，大约五十块钱
- What's it worth?  - At any hardware store, about 50 bucks.
老天，卡洛琳
Jesus, Carolyn.
不过我们碰见过有人付了两倍的价钱
But we've met people who paid twice what you did.
- 真的？ - 没错
- Really?  - Yeah.
你写了张支票吗，夫人？
You wrote a check, ma'am?
你邮寄给他们的吗？
Did you mail it to them?
不是，一个快递员来拿的
No, a courier picked it up.
怎么？
What?
如果他们利用邮政系统
Well, if they'd used the postal system...
那就是邮件诈欺，那我们就能去逮捕他们
it's mail fraud, and we can go after them.
否则，我们也做不了什么
Otherwise, there's not a lot we can do.
- 除非  - 除非什么？
- Unless...  - Unless what?
嗯，很多这样的疯子…
Well, a lot of these whack jobs...
他们为集团工作
they work in syndicates.
如果他们在别州兑现你的支票，就是联邦案件，我们能办
If they cashed your check out of state, it's federal we can act.
但是我们需要签字许可，你的和你银行的…
But we'd need a signed clearance from you from your bank...
我可以给你一张许可，只要能抓到这些狗娘养的
I'll give you one clearance if it will catch these sons of bitches.
- 你还有L-47表格吗？ - 有，也许在车里
- You have any more L-47s?  - Yeah, maybe in the car.
稍等一下
Wait a second.
有了，这里
Here we go. Here.
- 用我的笔  - 我有一支
- Use my pen.  - I got one.
好吧
Okay.
- 你把他放出去行吗？ - 喔，抱歉
- Would you let him out?  - Oh, sorry.
抱歉
Sorry.
走吧，这就对了
Here you go. That's right.
抱歉
Sorry.
我们所需要的，只是你的银行名字
All we need is the name of your bank...
你的帐号
...your account number...
还有你的签名，在下面
...and your signature down below.
- 要是运气好，这些家伙是业余的…  - 他还好吗？
- Any luck, these guys were amateurs...  - He all right?
好，他只是
Yeah, his...
- 在内华达州兑现支票  - 签在那里，你可以写上日期
...cashed your check in Nevada.  - Sign there. You can date it.
好了
There you go.
- 你还好吗？ - 他没事的
- You all right?  - He's fine.
- 非常感谢你俩  - 你想喝点水吗？
- Thanks for you both very much.  - Would you like some water?
没事的，我们走
Everything's fine. Let's go.
谢谢你们跑一趟
Thank you for coming.
你没吃药，对吧？
You didn't take your pills, did you?
他们让门开着，真是够了
They left the door open. It was bitchen!
不过是一扇开着的门，罗伊
It's just an open door, Roy.
这笔钱不多，但它能让我过一阵子了，差不多
Well, it's not a fortune, but it will keep me in diapers. Barely.
别看那些帘子，老兄，你应该知道的
Don't look at those drapes, man. You should've known.
昨晚又看到那个家伙了，恰克
Saw that guy again last night. Chuck.
我跟你说过的那人，这人有一个…
Guy I was telling you about. Guy with the...
有艘船
With the boat.
是的，弗莱切特，老兄，他可是条大鱼
Yeah, Frechette. Man, he's top-heavy.
- 老天，我到底…？ - 嘿，别说那句
- Jesus Christ, what am l...?  - Hey, don't say that.
- 别说什么？ - 你知道的
- Don't say what?  - You know what.
别说就是了
Just don't say it.
这可是大钱，罗伊
It's real money, Roy
如果真是大钱，那就得玩长期的，我不做长期的
If it's real money, it's long con. I don't do long con.
你最近没干过
You haven't done it lately.
别算我，弗兰克
Without me, Frank.
好吧
Okay.
我只是喜欢能够…
I'd just like to be able to...
你知道，时不时地带个姑娘去些好地方
You know, take a girl someplace nice once in a while.
这你还要另外付钱吗？
You have to pay extra for that?
- 嗨  - 嗨
- Hi.  - Hi.
三、四、五、六
Three, four, five, six and...
八包泰瑞顿烟
...eight packs of Tareyton.
三十六块，找五十
That's 36. Out of 50.
三七、三八、三九、四十，加上一十
Thirty-seven, 38, 39, 40 and 10
五十，谢谢
Is 50. Thank you.
下一个
Next.
这座城…
This town
是一座孤独之城
Is a lonely town
不是孤单之城
Not the only town
我喜欢这座城
I like it this town
这座城…
This town
能成就你
Is a make you town
或能毁了你
Or a break you town
带你堕落
bring you down town
（病人念咒呢）
Do no, do a, tray
俾格米土著
Oh, pygmies.
嗨，我是罗伊·沃勒，请接曼库索医生
Yeah, hi, this is Roy Waller calling for Dr. Mancuso.
- 他搬家了  - 什么？
- He moved.  - What?
他不住这里了，老兄
He doesn 't live here anymore, man.
- 你说什么“搬家”？ - 他走了
- What do you mean, "moved"?  - He's gone. He's get down.
- 你在唬弄我，他去哪里了？ - 他搬回东部去了
- You're shitting me. Where'd he go?  - He moved back east.
- 你啥意思，回东部？ - 他还欠我房租呢，老兄
- What you mean back east?  - He owes me back rent, man.
给我给联络方…喂？喂？
Give me a contact... Hello? Hello?
如果您需要打电话，请挂断之后再试一次
If you'd like to make a call, please hang up and try again.
罗伊，是我，法兰基
Roy, it's me. It's Frankie.
别这样，接电话，我知道挺难的，但快点吧
Come on, pick it up. I know it's tough, but come on.
罗伊，我是迪米特里，我那天晚上在“狂怒”俱乐部见过你
Roy, this is Dmitri. I met you at that club Rage the other night.
我真的很喜欢你的皮衣还有
I really liked your leather and...
好了啦，快点，接电话接电话接电话
All right, come on. Pick it up. Pick it up. Pick it up. Pick it up.
罗伊，别这样，老兄，快接
Roy, come on, man. Come on.
罗伊，我一个人在这小办公室里好寂寞
Roy, it's lonely in this little office all by myself.
罗伊，赶紧的
Roy, come on.
罗伊，我不想烦你，只是…嗯，我快死了，罗伊
Roy, I wouldn't bother you, but... Well, I'm dying, Roy.
是我的脾脏
It's my spleen.
我都感觉不到我的拇指
I can't feel my thumbs.
喂？
Hello.
罗伊，接电话，老兄
Roy, answer the phone, man.
我整个晚上都在看环球电视台，结果他们只说西班牙话
I've been watching Univision all night, and all they speak is Spanish.
搞什么啊？
What's going on?
说真格的，我要跟你谈谈，我想我出疹子了
But seriously, I want to talk to you because I think I've developed a rash.
别这样，老兄，快啦，你要急死我啊
Come on, man. Come on, you're killing me.
罗伊，别这样，什么鬼？我觉得自己像个小妞
Roy, come on, what the hell? I feel like a chick.
好吧，够了，我过来了
All right, that's it. I'm coming over.
罗伊？
Roy?
罗伊？好，我看到了
Roy? Okay, I see that.
我看…我看见你了，我知道你在
I see... I saw you. I know you're there.
快点，罗伊，真的，老兄
Come on, Roy. Really, man.
一、二、三
One, two, three.
把你鞋子脱掉
Take your shoes off.
- 什么？干嘛？ - 脱了鞋子，不然就不要进来
- What? Why?  - Take your shoes off, or you don't come in.
你没吃药，对不对？
You didn't take your pills, did you?
- 一、二、三  - 我正在脱
- One, two, three.  - I'm taking them off.
罗伊，别这样啦，我正在脱鞋，给我点时间
Roy, come on, man. I'm taking the shoes off. Give me a break over here.
好吧
Okay.
哦，上帝啊，那是什么味道？
Jesus Christ. Oh, God, what is that smell?
搞什么，你被清洁先生攻击了？
What, did you get attacked by Mr. Clean?
- 一、二、三  - 你得开扇窗户，伙计
- One, two, three.  - You gotta open a window, buddy.
- 别，别打开窗子  - 好，窗户关了
- No! No windows.  - Okay. Windows are closed.
窗户关了
Windows are closed.
你在找什么，蠢蛋？
You looking for something, sucker?
对，我的合伙人，你见到他了吗？
Yeah, my partner. Have you seen him?
他已经失踪大半个礼拜了，又高又帅
He's been missing most of the week. Tall good looking guy.
嘿，你可不可以小心地毯？你的食物都洒出来了
Hey, would you watch the rug? You're spilling food...
- 你没把鞋子脱掉  - 好，我这就把鞋子脱掉
- You didn't take your shoes off.  - Okay, I'm taking the shoes off.
好了，伙计，我这就脱
Okay, buddy. I'm taking them off.
看？脱掉了，鞋子脱了，好吧？
See? They're off. The shoes are off, okay?
捡起来了
Here you go.
哦，老兄，你真糟糕，你有没有吃药？
Oh, man, you are bad. Did you take your pills?
我把它们冲进水管里了，不小心
I spilled them down the drain by accident.
哦，罗伊，得了，老兄
Oh, Roy, come on, man
- 你给曼库索打电话了吗？ - 搬家了
- Did you call Mancuso?  - Moved.
搬家了…你是在唬我吧
Moved...You gotta be shitting me.
我就是这么说
That's what I said.
好，有了
Okay, here we go.
快点，来啊
Hurry. Come on.
来啊，走吧，快点，没事的
Come on, let's go. Come on. It's okay.
我要你呼吸，可以吗？只要一直呼吸
I want you to breathe, okay? Just keep breathing.
呼吸，很好
Breathe. Okay.
- 鞋子  - 好，好，鞋子，在这里
- Shoes  - Okay. Okay, shoes are... There you go.
- 你去清理食物  - 什么？
- You got food...  - What?
好，食物没了，我捡起所有的食物，行了吧？
Okay, food is gone. I'm picking up all the food, okay?
听我说，罗伊，你在听吗？
Listen to me, Roy. You listening?
我打几个电话，我婶婶看过一个精神医生，在她离婚后
I'm gonna make a couple of calls. My aunt saw this shrink after her divorce.
- 他真的帮到她了，他是好人  - 弗兰克
- He really helped her. He's a good guy.  - Frank...
嘿，罗伊，你得去看医生，明白？
Hey, Roy. You need to see someone. Okay?
别以为我这么做只是为了你
Don't think I'm doing this just for you.
你知道，你有钱，你可以退休了，我还有车贷呢，老兄
You know, you got money. You can retire. I got car payments, man.
我不需要合伙人这样子：
I don't need a partner who's like:
我内心与你同在，但现在就得这么办，我必须…
My heart goes out to you, but this is it now. I gotta make some...
你打完以后能不能擦干净？
Would you wipe that off when you're done with it?
擦话筒，把它擦干净
Wipe the receiver. Just wipe it off.
好，怎么样？你喜欢这样吗？
Okay. How's that? You like that?
怎么样？
How's that?
好啦，对不起，好吧
Okay, I'm sorry. Okay.
[哈里斯·克莱恩医生 医学博士]
你介意我把腿翘起来吗？这样我的背会舒服点
Do you mind if I put them up? It helps my back.
- 请便  - 谢了
- Go ahead.  - Thanks.
那么，你是洁癖之类的，罗伊
Well, you're something of a clean slate, Roy.
他们写着你在服药，但你不知道是哪种药物
They says you were on medication, but you don't know what kind.
对，没错，对，是一些粉红色的小药片
Yeah, okay, good. Yeah, they were these little pink tablets.
我觉得上面写着“CRC”，差不多那样
I think it said "CRC" on them. Something like that.
你是非法取得的？
You were getting them illegally?
是的，我是非法获得的，那又怎样？
Yes, I was getting them illegally. So what?
为什么呢？
Why?
那样我就不必告诉你们这些人了
So I wouldn't have to talk to somebody like you.
你知道它们是什么吗？
Do you know what they were?
知道
Yes.
照你吃的那种剂量，我得说你能坐直还真是走运了
At that dosage you've been taken, I'd say you're lucky to be sitting up straight.
好极了，你可以多给我一点吗？
That's great. Can you get me some more of them?
你确实说到了重点
You certainly get to the point.
而你绕开了，那么，你能不能给我药呢？
And you skirt it. So, can you get me the pills or not?
可以
Yes.
那么，咱们就把处方笺填一填吧
Well, then let's get that prescription pad out.
罗伊，通常我不会开出药方，除非我先跟病人聊过
Roy, usually I don't prescribe medicine unless I had a little chatted with the patient first.
如果你倾向于反对，这次会谈将非常简短
If you're inclined against that, this session will be quite brief.
你愿意跟我说说是什么在困扰你吗？
Would you like to tell me what's been bothering you?
我不喜欢待在户外，这我知道是叫“旷野恐惧症”，对吗？
I don't like being outdoors, which I know is called "agoraphobia." Right?
不准确，不过，没错
Incorrectly. But, yes.
- 还有吗？ - 灰尘，特别是在线条周围的
- Anything else?  - Dirt. Especially around moldings.
我不喜欢人家的鞋踩在我的地毯上
I don't like when people put shoes on my carpet.
显然，我经常抽搐，我发觉这非常令人沮丧，往轻了说
Obviously, I have a lot of tics. I find that very frustrating to say at least.
某些特定的事情令我分神，让我觉得恶心得想吐
Certain things distract me, make me feel sick to my stomach.
这种分神影响你近来的工作吗？
Have these distractions affected your work of late?
还有你的个人关系？
And your personal relationships?
什么个人关系？
What personal relationships?
你上一段是在什么时候，你知道，个人关系
When was the last time you were in one, you know, a relationship.
和女人吗？
With a woman?
- 很久以前了  - 五年？
- A long time ago. Five years?
- 十年？ - 继续，老兄
- Ten years?  - Keep going, man.
她叫什么名字？
What was her name?
海瑟
Heather.
你们结婚了吗？
Were you married?
孩子？
Kids?
也许
Maybe.
你没再见过她？
You haven't seen her since?
瞧，她走时带着黑眼圈，我打的，还有肚子里的种子
Look, she left me with a black eye, which I gave her, and a bun in the oven...
可能是任何人的，所以，不，我没见过她
...which might've come from anyone. So, no, I haven't.
瞧，医生，我上星期二整天盯着我地毯上的纤维
Look, doc, I spent last Tuesday watching fibers on my carpet.
我看着我的地毯的整段时间里，我在担心自己可能吐出来
And the whole time I was watching my carpet, I was worrying I might vomit.
整段时间我都在想
And the whole time I was thinking
“我是个成年人，我应该知道自己脑袋里是怎么回事”
"I'm a grown man. I should know what goes on in my head."
这事我想得越多
The more I thought about it...
就越觉得应该轰出自己的脑浆，一了百了
...the more I realized I should blow my brains out and end it all.
但后来我想，当我…我想到要轰出自己的脑浆
But then I thought, when I...if I thought more about blowing my brains out...
我就开始担心我该死的地毯会怎么样
...I started worrying about what that would do to my goddamn carpet.
明白？所以…
Okay? So...
那天还算是好的了，医生
That was a good day, doc.
我只想你给我一些药丸，让我凑合过日子
And I just want you to give me some pills and let me get on with my life.
- 罗伊  - 干嘛？
- Roy.  - What?
他就给你了，在办公室里？
He just gave them to you at the office?
他说这是新药，普利发什么的
He said they were new. Prefex something-or-other.
- 你感觉好些了？ - 一点点
- You feel better?  - A little.
你要开始干活了吗？
You want to work soon?
你觉得你可以控制那个…
Think you can you control the...?
- 什么？ - 没事
- What?  - Nothing.
- 请问是哪个城市？ - 林地山市，加州
- What city, please?  - Woodland Hills, California.
- 姓名，先生？ - 芬顿，海瑟
- Name, sir?  - Fenton, Heather.
- 你能拼一下吗？ - F、E、N
- Can you spell that?  - F-E-N...
令人忧郁
Came blue and in
越洋而来
from across the sea
在那边徘徊
It lingered there
轻触你的头发
to touch your hair
你与我同行
and you walk with me
整个夏天
All summer long
我们唱了一支歌
we sang a song
后来我们漫步
and then we stroll
嗨，如果是你打来，那这就是我，请在哔一声之后留言
Hi. If that's you, then this is me. So leave a message after the beep.
- 喂，我是…  - 喂？？
- Hello, this is...  - Hello?
那个，你知道，我们常常吵架
Well, you know, we fought a lot.
吵什么？
About what?
你想呢？那时候我难得清醒
What do you got? I wasn't sober a lot then.
你现在清醒吗？
Are you now?
所以，有些夜晚，她就没回家
So some nights, she just didn't come home.
她怀孕两个月了才告诉我
She was pregnant two months before she even told me about it.
哦，你经常想起她吗？
Yeah. Do you think about her much?
你知道的，本来会怎样，本来该怎样
You know, what could have been, what might have been.
- 还有那孩子？ - 如果有孩子的话
- And the baby?  - If there's a baby.
- 你会想吗？ - 有时会，很少
- Do you think about that?  - Sometimes. Rarely.
你知道，比如我要是看见一辆校车或是…
You know, like, if I see a school bus or...
我会想“那些孩子里有没有小罗伊”？
I'll wonder, "Is one of those kids Roy Jr.?"
他，如果是男孩，现在应该多大了？
He, if he's a he, would be how old now?
他会有十四岁
He'd be 14.
十四岁，准备成为男人了
Fourteen, ready to be a man.
是啊，如果是男孩的话
Yeah. If he's a he.
如果他存在
If he is at all.
恭喜你，你买到了一个星期的药量
Congratulations. You bought yourself a week's worth.
谢了
Thanks.
听着，医生
Listen, doc...
你知道有什么办法…
...do you know of a way...
只是为了搞清楚，你知道的…
...just to find out, you know...
一个人打电话给前妻又没什么错
There's nothing wrong with a man telephoning his ex-wife.
我昨晚试过了，可是我一个词也说不出来
I tried that last night, and I couldn't say a word.
你能打电话给她吗？
So could you call her?
- 我不知道，罗伊，我  - 拜托，只是为了搞清楚
- I don't know, Roy. I...  - Please. It's just to find out.
- 现在？ - 不，等我…我走了以后
- Now?  - No, when I...after I'm gone.
你方便的时候
When you can.
- 好吧  - 太棒了
- Okay.  - That's great.
谢谢你
Thank you.
那我星期二再见你？
So I'm gonna see you on Tuesday?
嗯…为什么？我是说，我有药
Well... Why? I mean, I have the meds.
那么，我看你来决定吧
Well, I guess that's your call.
- 好吧  - 保重
- Okay.  - Take care.
哈罗？
Hello.
罗伊？我是克莱恩医生，我…
Roy? This is Dr. Klein. I...
- 喂？ - 嘿
- Hello?  - Hey.
听着，我刚和海瑟通完电话
Listen, I just got off the phone with Heather.
我们聊得很愉快
We had a very nice conversation.
- 她想跟我说话吗？ - 不，她不想
- Does she want to speak with me?  - No, she doesn 't.
我很遗憾，她不知道这可能对你的治疗有帮助
I'm sorry. She didn't understand it might help with your therapy.
你告诉她我在治疗
You told her I was in therapy.
不，我说我是精神科医生，我不能撒谎，罗伊，所以…
No, I told her I'm a psychiatrist. I can't lie, Roy. So...
- 不过安吉拉想跟你谈谈  - 谁？
- Angela wants to talk to you though.  - Who?
安吉拉，你的女儿
Angela, your daughter.
她知道你是她爸爸，说她真的想见你
She knows you're her father and says she really wants to meet you.
该死
Shit.
嘿
Hey.
- 安吉拉？ - 你是罗伊？
- Angela?  - You Roy?
没错
Yeah.
- 你十四岁了？ - 是的
- So you're 14?  - Yep.
你什么时候出来的？
So when did you get out?
- 什么？ - 出狱
- What?  - Of prison.
我从没坐过牢
I've never been in prison.
是你妈告诉你的？
Did your mom tell you that?
一开始她跟我说你死了
At first she told me you were dead.
后来又说你死了最好
Then she said you might as well be.
我没死，我做古董行的
I'm not dead. I'm in antiques.
是啊，那个医生就是这么说的，在电话里
Yeah, that's what the doctor said on the phone.
他说这话的时候，妈妈就开始笑
When he said that, Mom started to laugh.
你饿吗？
You hungry?
不介意吃点东西吧？
Do you mind eating?
只因为我待在室内感觉会好些
It's just I'd feel better somewhere indoors.
待在户外有时会让我不舒服
I get uncomfortable sometimes being outside.
- 真的？ - 是的
- Really?  - Yeah.
- 你在瞪我  - 对不起
- You're staring.  - I'm sorry.
没事，我也常常这样
It's okay. I used to do it too.
对着你的照片，看自己是不是遗传了你的鼻子，你的眼睛
Looked at your picture, see if I got your nose, your eyes.
妈总说我运气好，只遗传到你的手肘
Mom used to say I got lucky and only got your elbows.
我以为你肚子不饿
Thought you weren't hungry.
如果你湿了鞋，不如干脆下河游泳
If you're gonna get wet, might as well go swimming.
那么，你是在上学，对吗？
So you're in school, right?
现在不用，暑假
Not now. It's summer.
哦，对，是这样的
Oh, yeah. Okay, that's right.
上学真的很重要
School is really important.
如果有什么事可以再来一遍，我一定会更用功读书
If I had anything to do over again, I would've worked harder in school.
你退学了？
You drop out?
你就是这样成了罪犯？
That how you ended up a criminal?
我来付就好了，麦克
I'll take it, Mike.
没事的，你知道，不管你做什么
It's okay, you know. Whatever you do.
每个人一生中都做过坏事
Everybody's done something bad in their life.
我是卖古董的
I'm in antiques.
如果你以它为职业，那只不过是一堆事情串在一起
If you make it a career, it's just a bunch of something strung together.
别说屁话，好吗？我不是罪犯，抱歉
Cut the shit, Okay? I'm not a criminal. I'm sorry.
什么？你用那个字眼？屁话？
What? What was that word you used? Shit?
嘿，那个…
Hey, that...
你不该这样子说话
You're not supposed to talk like that.
[加州社会保障卡 罗伊·沃勒]
嘿，嘿嘿
Hey, hey. Hey.
- 我只是…我摆东西都有固定位置  - 好吧
- I just... I have things a certain way.  - Okay.
等等，那是她的车在车道上
Wait. That's her car in the driveway.
你得停在这里，停车
You gotta stop here. Stop!
也许有时间我们可以去打保龄球
Maybe we could go bowling sometime.
这是我的私人线路
This is my private line.
生日那天妈妈给我的
My mom got it for my birthday...
因为我朋友凯莉老在半夜以后打电话
because my friend Carrie kept calling after midnight.
还你
Here you go.
很高兴见到你，老爸
Nice to meet you, Dad.
走吧
Go.
有什么比家人更重要？
What's more important than family?
然后，还有什么比净化你家人喝的水更重要？
Then what could be more important than purifying the water your family drinks?
华特生两千型为你提供今天最清洁的滤水系统
The Waterson 2000 offers you the cleanest filtration system available today.
谢利克林先生，请你稍等一下？谢谢
Mr. Schlickling, can you hold on just one moment? Thank you.
怎么了？
What?
你怎么了？换了洗发精还是什么？
What's going on with you? You switch shampoos or something?
那些药片起作用了？
Those pills working?
是啊，好，我很高兴咱俩有一个人是快乐的
Yeah. All right. Well, I'm glad one of us is happy.
你觉得我们能从那个家伙身上榨出多少钱？
How much you think we can take that guy for?
- 恰克，有船的那个家伙  - 你是认真的？
- Chuck, with the boat.  - You serious?
我琢磨我欠你一份人情
I figure I owe you one.
老兄，这太棒了
Man, that's great!
谢利…里克先生？嗨，抱歉，你考虑太久了，没奖品给你
Mr. Schlick-licker? Hi, I'm sorry. You waited too long. No prize for you.
帅呆了，老兄
That's awesome, man!
抱歉
Sorry.
- 到哪里可以找到他？ - 薄荷犀牛
- Where'd you find him?  - Spearmint Rhino.
一个月前见过他在那卖G丸给一对情侣
Watched him drop a couple G's there a month ago.
薄荷犀牛
Spearmint Rhino.
- 对，那是个男人去的…  - 我知道那是什么地方
- Yeah, that's a gentlemen's...  - I know what it is.
就在这里
It's right here.
- 他是做什么的？ - 进出口贸易
- What does he do?  - Import-export.
- 他姓什么？ - 弗莱切特，恰克·弗莱切特
- What's his last name?  - Frechette. Chuck Frechette.
- 怎么拼？ - F、R
- How do you spell that?  - F-R...
我不知道，他来自道尼市
I don't know. He's from Downey.
他没有后台，对吗？
He's not connected, is he?
没有没有，他跟帮派，就像这样：
No, no. He and the mob, they're like this:
这王八蛋甚至没给小费
Son of a bitch didn't even tip.
我粗粗算过，至少可以刮他三万美金
I figure, on short notice, he could scratch up at least 30 grand.
不止
More.
我们用“牙买加变换”，他认识你，所以你当绳子，我当内应
We'll pull the Jamaican switch. He knows you, so you're rope. I'm inside.
你觉得他懂不懂一点国际金融？
You think he knows anything about international finance?
你在低语吗？
Are you whispering?
- 干嘛低语？ - 我有吗？
- Why are you whispering?  - I am?
- 嗨，开保险箱，劳驾  - 没问题
- Hi. Safety deposit box, please.  - Sure.
嗨，我想开我的保险箱，三六六号，劳驾
Hi. I'd like access to my safety deposit box, 366, please.
没问题，沃勒先生
Certainly, Mr. Waller.
签名以及密码，劳驾
Signature and pass code, please.
- 你需要小间吗？ - 不，谢谢，我没事
- Would you like a booth?  - No, thanks. I'll be fine.
英镑对美金的话…
When it's sterling versus dollars and...
对有些人而言，钱就是…
For some people, money is...
钱是一部没有字幕的外语片
Money is a foreign film without subtitles.
- 弗兰克  - 你要在哪里碰面，帅哥？
- Frank.  - Where do you want to meet, sexy?
- 你说什么“哪里”？还有哪里？犀牛  - 好
- What do you mean, "where"? Where else? The Rhino.  - Okay
- 一个小时  - 你不想早一点到吗？
- One hour.  - Hey, you don 't wanna get there early?
我得挂了
I gotta go.
还记得我吗？
Remember me?
你刚好来附近吗？
You just in the neighborhood?
搭公车，我可以进去吗？
Took the bus. Think I could come in a sec?
- 一、二、三  - 真不赖
- One, two, three.  - Nice!
不错，你这地方
It's nice, your place.
你能不能小心地毯，拜托？
Could you watch the carpet, please?
对不起
Sorry.
能不能请你脱掉鞋子？
Could you please take your shoes off?
好，不好意思
Oh, yeah, sorry.
发生什么事了？
So, what's going on?
妈妈和我吵了一架，隔一段时间就会有一次
Mom and I had sort of a fight. Happens once in a while.
我通常会离家一两天，等她冷静
I usually take off for a day or two to let her calm down.
离家出走？
Take off?
通常我就去凯莉家…只是她度假去了
Normally, I go to Carrie's......only she's on vacation.
我就想，我们上回聊得还算愉快
And I thought, since we seemed to hit it off so well last time...
我可以…我可以睡你的沙发
I could...I could sleep on your couch.
你要待在这里？
You want to stay here?
对啊，作为回报，我可以帮你打扫还是什么的
Well, I could pay you back by cleaning up or something.
- 你戴那个是要读书吗？你的眼镜？ - 什么？
- Do you wear those to read? Your glasses?  - What?
你这样看起来好老气
They make you kind of old.
哦，不是，这是为了…
Oh, no, these are for...
我得走了！有一个重要的业务会议
I gotta go! I got a big business meeting.
- 这么晚了？ - 古董，是不等人的
- This late?  - Antiques, they wait for no man.
我留你一个人在这不要紧吧？
Is it all right if I leave you here alone?
当然，我看电视就行了
Sure, I can just watch TV.
你没电视？
You don't have a TV?
你居然没电视？
Seriously? You don't have a TV?
那里有沙发，如果你要坐的话
There's a couch, if you want to sit.
或是那边，只要你愿意，或者沙发
Or over there, if you prefer. Or the couch.
要不要我回来路上给你带点什么？
Do you want me to pick you up something on the way back?
- 比如，什么好呢，冰淇淋，对吗？ - 好啊
- Like, what is it, ice cream, right?  - Sure.
纽约超富奇冰淇淋，我最喜欢的口味
New York Super Fudge Chunk. That's my favorite flavor.
- 纽约  - 超富奇冰淇淋
- New York...  - Super Fudge Chunk.
巧克力，好，现在听好…
Chocolate, yeah. Okay, now listen...
不要，不要给任何人开门，好吗？
...don't, don't open the door for anybody, all right?
好
Okay
一、二、三
One, two, three.
很赞哦
All right!
这是你的，甜心
Here you go, sweetie.
是啊，太好了
Yeah, all right.
东西都来了，宝贝
Here we go, babe.
- 鲍勃，见到你真好  - 亚顿，希望没有让你等太久
- Bob, good to see you!  - Arden, hope I didn't keep you.
在那里，他没注意到你来了
Over there. He missed you coming in.
什…什么？
Wh..what?
在那里，他没注意到你来了
Over there. He missed you coming in.
嗨，凯特，来杯啤酒行吗？海尼根？
Hey, Kate! Can I get a beer? A Heinie?
多谢
Thanks.
- 这样行了吗？ - 咱们坐
- That do the trick?  - Let's sit.
我说过你会喜欢这里的
I told you you were gonna like it here.
不会吧
No way!
酒来了，甜心
Here you go, sweetie.
- 鞋子真不错，姑娘  - 谢了，宝贝
- Love them shoes, girl.  - Thank you, baby.
嗨，鲍勃
Hey, Bob!
嗨，恰克，我不知道你在这
Hey, Chuck, I didn't know you were here.
嗨，恰克·弗莱切特，这位是亚顿
Hey, Chuck Frechette, this is Arden...
你好
Hiya.
嗨
Hey...
我有点事要谈，你能不能先…？
I gotta do a little business, you mind if...?
当然，鲍勃，我不是有意…抱歉，我会…
Sure, Bob. I didn't mean to...Sorry. I'll be...
- 很高兴认识你，我会在这边  - 太好了
- Nice meeting you. I'll be over here.  - Great.
鱼已经上钩了
That's fish in a barrel.
他伤自尊了，你准备好了吗？
He's piqued. You good to go?
- 教皇会在木头上拉屎吗？ - 说“好”就行
- Does the pope poo in the woods?  - Just say yes.
- 再见，鲍勃  - 明天一早见，亚顿
- I'll see you, Bob.  - I'll see you in the morning, Arden.
- 嗨  - 嗨
- Hi.  - Hi.
- 晚上有大计划啊  - 哦，不是给我买的
- Big night planned.  - Oh, it's not for me.
- 是的，一共是十二块七毛三  - 好
- Right. That's $ 12.73.  - Okay.
找你十五块
Out of 15.
十三、十四、十五，你孩子来过夜？
Thirteen, 14, 15. You got kids overnight?
罗伊？妈妈为什么离开你？
Roy? Why did Mom leave you?
这个你得问她了
Well, you'd have to ask her that.
问过了，她说她不想提这件事
I did. She said she didn't wanna talk about it.
还臭骂了你一顿
Called you names.
所以我们才会吵架
That's why we got in a fight.
她说你是坏人
She said you were a bad guy.
你看起来不像坏人
You don't seem like a bad guy.
这正是我干得好的地方
That's what makes me good at it.
反正，我不觉得你是坏人
Well, I don't think you're a bad guy.
晚安
Good night.
里面有人
Someone's in here!
我觉得这不可接受，我觉得不可接受
I think it's disrespectful. I just think it's disrespectful.
- 嘿，快点  - 一、二、三
- Hey, come on.  - One, two, three.
真希望你在场，我把他牵进来了，老兄
I wish you could've been there. I reeled him in, man.
- 哈利路亚！你藏了个小妞在家啊？ - 你在干嘛啊？
- Hallelujah! You got a chick in there?  - What are you doing?
慌乱什么呀？
What's the hubbub?
你一离开那里，他就走下吧台凳，他上钩了
The second you left the place, he was off his barstool. He's in.
- 他上钩了，他想今晚会面  - 好吧
- He's in. He wants to meet tonight.  - All right.
推到明天
Push it till tomorrow.
先让他的贪心发挥下想象力
Let his greed meet his imagination.
早安
Morning.
Good morning.
我给你做了鸡蛋
I made you eggs.
可以
That's okay.
早先来的那个家伙是谁？
So who was that guy who came by earlier?
生意伙伴
Business associate.
他叫什么名字？
Well, what was his name?
弗兰克
Frank.
你怎么会不想让他看到我？
How come you didn't want him to see me?
我不是不想让他看到你…
It's not that I don't want him to see you...
你不觉得早餐应该吃鸡蛋吗？健康的东西
Don't you think you should eat eggs for breakfast? Something healthy.
我不喜欢鸡蛋
I don't like eggs.
反正你这里只有金枪鱼，一大堆金枪鱼
Anyways, all you've got here is tuna. Lots of tuna.
还有一盒电视餐
And one TV dinner?
电视餐是不错，你也得有电视配才行啊
TV dinners are cool. You should get the TV to go with them.
我喜欢金枪鱼
I like tuna fish.
嗨，妈
Hi, Mom.
不要
No.
如果我是又怎样？那又怎样？他是我老爸
So what if I am? So? He's my father.
我不在乎，我不在乎！
Well, I don't care. I don't care!
如果我想的话我会的
Well, I will if I want!
不，我知道
No. I know.
好，我答应你
Okay, I promise.
好，拜
Okay, bye.
她生气了？
Is she mad?
是气我，不是你
At me, not you.
- 她说她要报警  - 哦，天啊
- She said she was gonna call the police.  - Oh, God.
哦，天啊
Oh, God.
但现在她只要我及时回去上暑期班
But now she just wants me home in time for summer school.
什么时候开课？
When's that start?
星期一
Monday.
今天是星期四
Today's Thursday.
没关系的，对吧？
That's okay, isn't it?
三，四
Three, four.
用力吐气，很好，非常好
Let it out. Good, very good.
你的地毯上有污点
You've got stains on your carpet.
你就是在想这个事儿，我地毯上的污点？
Is that what you were thinking about, stains on my carpet?
可以坐起来了
You can sit up.
是的，地毯上的污渍…
Yeah, carpet stains...
还有个十四岁少女，我几乎不认识，住在我家里
...and that I have a 14-year-old girl I barely know living in my house.
相信我，他们没那么难办，小孩
Trust me, they're not so difficult, kids.
通常，你要确保他们吃蔬菜
Mostly, you have to make sure they eat their vegetables...
别熬夜太晚，别看太多电视
...don't stay up too late, don't watch too much TV.
然后，试着尽量诚实和开放地面对他们
Otherwise, just try to be as honest and open with them as possible.
- 尽量诚实和开放  - 对吧？
- Honest and open with them as possible.  - Right?
对
Right!
第三台需要支票检查
I need a check okay on three.
经理请到第三台批准支票
Manager for a check okay on three, please.
那一台排队较短
The line for that one's shorter.
不要，这台比较好
No, this one's better.
五磅苹果装需要检查价格
We need a price check on a five-pound bag of Red Delicious.
老爸，快点，快点
Dad, hurry! Hurry!
俾格米土著
Pygmies!
意大利面，我们要做意大利面
Spaghetti. We're making spaghetti.
是是，欢乐时光，欢乐时光
Yeah. Happy times. Happy times.
来了
Here it comes.
你知道…意大利的厨师们
You know the...the chefs in Italy...
他们说，如果你把面条扔出去黏得住就表示熟了
they say the spaghetti's ready if you throw it and it sticks.
啤酒
Beer.
干杯
Cheers.
我说不好
I don't know.
- 没有浇酱汁吗？ - 这是哎哟哟意大利面
- No sauce to go over it?  - It's spaghetti alio olio!
还有罗勒叶子在里面
And it's got basil leaves in it.
看到叶子没？
See the leaves?
好好享受吧
Enjoy it.
- 华特斯？ - 沃勒，不用找了
- Walters?  - Waller. Keep the change.
现在我高兴了
I'm happy now.
- 你真的不要喝点什么？ - 谢谢，我两个小时内要搭飞机
- You sure you don't want something?  - Thanks, I gotta fly in two hours.
- 你去哪里？ - 凤凰城
- Where're you up to?  - Phoenix.
有个客户开了个账户，兑换英镑和欧元，我得去把住他的手
A client's opening an account to bridge the pound and Euro. I gotta hold his hand.
能不能请你把这个弄热一点？
Would you please heat this up?
- 这么糟糕啊？ - 就是啊
- That bad?  - Yeah.
对有些老乡来说，钱就像是一部没有字幕的外语片
For some folks, money is a foreign film without subtitles.
- 好了，谈正事吧  - 谈正事吧
- Anyway, to the business at hand.  - To the business at hand.
我有个规矩，恰克，简单就是安全
I have one rule, Chuck. Simple is safe.
我会尽量少跟你讲我以及我做的事
I'll tell you as little as possible about me and what I do...
但会尽量多讲我们要做的事情，让你感觉舒适
...but as much as I need to to make you comfortable with what we're doing.
我们要做什么？
What are we doing?
五千英镑，在银行汇兑部门工作的好处
Five thousand pounds sterling. A perk of working in exchange at a bank.
- 这是谁的？ - 不是哪个人的
- Whose is it?  - No one's particular
没算进去的钱，浮在帐簿上的一层奶油
Just money unaccounted for, floating on top of the books like a layer of cream.
而他就把它刮下来
And he just scoops it off.
嗯，比那个…鲍勃
Well, it's a little more... Bob!
比那要复杂一点，但再说一次，简单就是安全
It's a little more complicated than that, but again, simple is safe.
你为什么不自己留起来？
Why not keep the money yourself?
作为银行雇员，想要兑换货币，都会留下记录还会被质问
As a bank employee...any attempt to change currency is recorded and questioned.
鲍勃就有记录
Bob has a record.
而你，在另一方面，没人会眨下眼
You, on the other hand, no one bats an eye.
现在，我希望你能给我点东西
Now, I hope you have something for me.
- 五千块，美金  - 恭喜你
- Five grand, American.  - Congratulations.
- 根据今天的汇率你刚赚了  - 两千五百六十七美元，从互联网上查的
- At today's exchange rate you made...  - $2567. Looked it up on the Internet.
他反应真快
He's fast.
互联网这东西，是种时尚，我就搞不懂
That Internet thing, that's a fad. I can't figure it out.
我也不行，但我女儿是行家
Well, neither can I, but my daughter's a wiz.
- 怎么，你有个女儿？ - 两个，十五岁和十二岁
- What? You have a daughter?  - Two. Fifteen and 12.
- 真不错，我女儿十四岁  - 一场暴乱，对吗？
- Wonderful, I have a 14-year-old.  - It's a riot, huh?
小小的胸罩就挂在浴帘杆上
Little training bras hanging from the shower rods.
对啊，而且什么都有股口香糖味
Yeah, and everything smells like gum.
你怎么让他们出门的？我女儿整天都待在家里
How do you get them outside? Because mine sits at home all day.
- 夏天是最糟糕的  - 对
- Summer is the worst. The worst.  - Yeah
- 真是疯了，真是狂野  - 他学得真像
- It's crazy. It's wild.  - He sounds just like him.
我问你个事，亚顿，你一次最多可以捞多少？
Let me ask you something, Arden. How much could you do this for?
按规矩，我们从来不超过一万
Well, as a rule, we never go north of 10.
你手边有多少钱？
How much could you get your hands on?
- 很多  - 那好
- A lot.  - All right.
- 一言为定  - 合作愉快
- Put it there.  - Let's play ball.
- 恰克，宝贝，让我也尝点甜头啊  - 好
- Chucky, baby, give me some sugar.  - Yeah.
- 待会见？ - 和平，两根手指头
- See you later?  - Peace. Two fingers.
和平？
Peace?
- 浑蛋  - 没给小费？
- Asshole.  - Didn't tip him?
又来了
Do it again
- 停车票卡  - 是的，他是个混球
- Tickets, please.  - Yeah, he's a jackass.
再见，混球
See you, jackass.
老兄，我看我们一会儿就花了两千块
Man, I thought we were out 2 grand there for a second.
你要赚钱，就得先花钱
You gotta spend money if you wanna make money.
对，你得先赚才有得花，兄弟
Yeah, you gotta make it to spend it. Brother.
“什么都有股口香糖味”
"Everything smells like gum"?
那是怎么回事？
What was that about?
带你去看更好点
It's easier if I show you.
安吉拉？
Angela?
安吉拉，我回来了
Angela, I'm back.
安吉拉，弗兰克来了
Angela, Frank's here!
嘿
Hey.
安吉拉？
Angela?
她不在，一定是回她妈那里去了
She's not here. She must have gone back to her mom's.
这个辣妹希拉里说“我还单身，宝贝”
This teenybopper Hillary says, "I am single, baby."
- 她通常都去哪里？ - 我不知道
- Where does she usually go?  - I don't know.
这样不好，罗伊，对你对我们都不好
This is no good, Roy. It's no good for you or us.
这和我们一点关系都没有
It's got nothing to do with us.
嘿
Hey!
俾格米土著
Pygmies.
是啊
Yeah.
- 这就是坏消息，老兄  - 你没必要这样看待此事
- This is bad news, man.  - You don't have to put it like that.
- 你去哪里了？ - 没去哪
- Where have you been?  - Nowhere.
好吧，你上哪里去了？
Okay. Where did you go?
我只是出去了，我去游戏场，半英里远而已
I just went out. I went to the arcade. It's like a half a mile away.
这里好闷，闻着像是来苏水
It's stuffy in here. It smells like Lysol.
你到底跑去哪里了？
Where the hell were you?
我现在就要知道，不然我就打电话给你妈
I wanna know right now or I'm calling your mother!
我刚告诉你了，我去游戏场
I just told you. I went to the arcade.
你干嘛偷偷摸摸的从后门进来？
Why did you sneak back in?
我就是这样出门的，我没有钥匙锁门
That's how I left. I didn't have keys to lock the door.
哦，那你没看到我的车吗？
So you didn't see my car?
天哪，你比老妈还烦
Jeez, you're worse than Mom.
安吉拉，听好，我很高兴见到你，真的，但是我有工作
Angela, listen, I'm glad I met you, I'm glad we met, I really am, but I've got a business...
我有伙伴，而且我的东西有一定的规矩，就这样！
...and I've got a partner and I've got things a certain way, and that's it!
所以，你知道，我想最好…
So, you know, I think it'd be better...
对于你，最重要的是，我明早就送你回家
...for you, most of all, if tomorrow morning I took you back home.
- 我做错了什么？ - 什么都没有
- What did I do wrong?  - You didn't do anything wrong.
我只是出去一趟！天啊！我没喝酒也没嗑药
I just went out! God, I didn't even... I didn't drink, I didn't get high!
更没从你那只笨狗里拿半毛钱
I didn't take any money from your stupid dog!
怎样，你从没听说过银行吗？
What, you never heard of a bank?
你所做的是错的，还有
That is wrong what you did, and...
你太爱管闲事，还有
...you're a Nosy Parker, and...
女孩子家不应该这么野
And that's no way for a young lady to behave!
你真丢脸
Shame on you!
安吉拉？
Angela?
宝贝？
Sweetheart?
- 我不是要把你赶走  - 我不想待的地方就不待
- I wasn't kicking you out.  - I won't stay where I'm not wanted!
- 我没有不要你  - 骗人
- It's not that I don't want you.  - Fooled me.
- 闹够了没有？ - 没有，让我走
- Will you stop?  - Don't! Let me go!
你只是不想让我回去告诉妈说，她没看错你
You don't want me going home to Mom thinking she was right all along!
住手
Stop!
你和她那些男朋友没两样
You're just like one of her boyfriends!
我只是你们为了对付她而必须处理的东西
I'm just something you have to deal with in order to screw her!
- 拜托，你知道不是这样  - 甚至他们会告诉我说自己是做什么的
- Please, you know that's not true.  - Even they tell me what they do for a living!
对啊，古董商总是把大笔现金藏在家里，和枪放在一起
Oh yeah, antiques dealers always keep large stacks of cash in their homes right next to their guns.
好，好，行了吧？对不起，只不过…
Okay. Okay. All right? I'm sorry. It's just...
我不是
I'm not...
我不懂怎么做一个爸爸，行吗？你知道吗？
I'm not very good at being a dad. Okay? You know? All right?
我连自己都搞不定
I barely get by being me.
- 宝贝，拜托  - 不要
- Come on, sweetheart, please...  - Don't!
跟我回家吧，我们再叫个大比萨来吃
Come on back home with me, and we can get a big pizza again.
你可以整个周末都待在这里，只要你愿意，行吗？
You can stay the whole weekend if you want, all right?
你怎么会有枪？
Why do you have a gun?
预防万一
In case.
万一什么？
In case what?
这很难解释
It's hard to explain.
沃勒，不用找了
Waller. Keep the change.
- 屁话！ - 不
- Bullshit!  - Nope.
不是屁话，注意你的餐桌语言
No bullshit. And watch your language at the table.
- 你是个骗子？ - 是行骗艺术家
- You're a con man?  - Con artist.
老千，火柴人，窝囊废，随你怎么叫
A flimflam man, matchstick man, loser. Whatever you want to call it.
那个家伙，弗兰克呢？
And that guy, Frank?
他是我的伙伴，我的徒弟
He's my partner. My protege
- 教我几招吧  - 什么？
- Teach me something.  - What?
- 教我怎么骗人  - 你在开玩笑
- Teach me something, a con.  - You're funny.
不是，好嘛，真的！教教我
No, come on, really! Teach me something.
- 我什么也不会教你  - 为什么？
- I'm not teaching you anything.  - Why not?
因为你是一个聪明，天真，漂亮的女孩
Because you're a bright, innocent, beautiful girl...
我不想象其他事情一样搞砸这事
...and I'm not gonna screw that up like everything else.
真的？
Really?
- 什么？ - 你真的那么想？
- What?  - You think that?
我很漂亮？
That I'm beautiful?
不是
No.
那为什么不教我？因为没赚头？
Then why won't you? Because crime doesn't pay?
不是，有赚头，只是没那么多
No, it does. It does. Just not very well.
- 你看起来干得不错  - 我没有
- You seem to be doing okay.  - I'm not.
相信我，我做的事并不好玩
Believe me, it's no fun doing what I do.
一直以来就是从无辜群众那里偷钱罢了
All the time it's stealing from people who don't deserve it.
老人家，胖子，寂寞的人
Old people, fat people. Lonely.
很多时候，让我觉得很厌恶
A lot of the time, I feel sick about it.
那你为什么要做？
Then why do you do it?
我才不像你想的那样天真呢，我和男生做过些事情
I'm not as innocent as you think. I've done stuff with boys.
我和男生做过些事情，要是我告诉你
I've done stuff with boys, if I told you...
- 你会吐在这里的  - 那就别讲
- you'd throw up right here.  - Then don't tell me.
- 那你教我  - 不！最终决定
- Then teach me something!  - No! Final.
去年的圣诞舞会，我和一个叫乔什·沃德的男孩一起去的
At the Christmas dance last year, I went with this boy Josh Ward.
- 他很帅，我真的真的喜欢他  - 我没在听
- He's cute, and I really really liked him.  - I'm not listening.
舞会结束后，我们去凯莉家，我们上了楼
After the dance, we went to Carrie's, and we went upstairs
然后他把我压倒在床上
and he pushed me against the bed...
- 没听  - 然后他的手
- Not listening!  - ...and he took his hand...
- 不！好了！我就教你一招  - 真的？
- No! All right. I'll show you one thing!  - You will?
谢谢你，谢谢
Thank you, thank you!
- 好啦，行了  - 谢谢你
- All right, okay...  - Thank you!
但你以后绝不能再干，而且要忘了它，同意吗？
But then you're never gonna do it again, and you're gonna forget it. Agreed?
圣母玛利亚
Holy Mary.
规则一：永远不要在自己家附近下手
Rule number one: Never work near where you live.
不要乱搞…
Don't shit...
规则二：什么也别写下来
Rule number two: Don't write anything down.
好了，我要你待在车里，行吗？
All right, I want you to stay in the car, okay?
嘿！你待在车里行吗？
Hey! Would you stay in the car?
[昨天的中奖号码 6 18 30 49 60]
我要签二十二期的乐透彩
I'd like to play this for the drawing on the 22nd.
你知道同一个月里出现相同号码的机率有多低？
You know the odds of the same numbers hitting in the same month? Same numbers hitting in ever?
相同号码有史以来的几率？
Same numbers hitting in ever?
所以我才改了一个号码
Well, that's why I changed one.
你这是在浪费钱
You're wasting your dollar.
嘿，你是他的财务顾问吗？不是
Hey. You his financial adviser? No.
你只是个便利商店的收银员
You're a cashier at a convenience store.
收下他的钱把二十二期彩券给他
Take his dollar and give him a ticket on the 22nd.
- 你有这个架势了  - 我生来如此
- You're ready for this.  - I was born ready.
真高兴我错过了那一天
Glad I missed that day.
好了，这场游戏里需要了解最重要的事情
Okay, the most important thing to understand about this game is...
有百分之九十都是不确定因素
...ninety percent of it is variable.
无论多好的计划，你几乎总是会遇到状况
No matter how good a plan is, you almost always get thrown a curve.
所以你一定要有弹性，要会随机应变
So you gotta be flexible, prepared to roll with anything.
- 我明白  - 就这两件事
- I'll do it.  - Just the 2.
然而，你能够控制的一件事，就是你的目标是谁
The one thing you can control, though, is who your mark is.
永远别跟那些不买你要卖的东西的人玩
Never play someone who isn't buying what you're selling.
你在想“老爸，我在卖什么呢”？
You're thinking, "Dady, dady, what am I selling?"
好了，你就是要推销自己
Well, what you're selling is you.
越老越好
And the older the better.
要提防夫妻，你不能让任何人跟目标讲悄悄话，除了你
Beware of couples. You don't want anyone whispering in your mark's ear, but you.
还有，以上帝的名义，你得确定你要骗的人不是在骗你
For God's sake, make sure the person you're conning isn't conning you.
就是这样，好了，我们来找个冤大头吧
That's good. All right. Let's go kick some butt.
- 这有人用吗？ - 没有
- This taken?  - No.
你确定？你衣服好多
You sure? You've got a lot.
这没什么，你应该看看打少棒赛时的我
This is nothing. You ought to catch me during Little League season.
三个儿子
Three boys.
他们可爱吗？
Any of them cute?
赛门差不多你这年纪，不过你都猜不到，他太皮了
Simon's about your age. Though you'd never guess. He's so hyper.
- 我要去买汽水，你需要什么吗？ - 不了，谢谢
- I'm gonna get a soda. Want anything?  - No, thanks. Honey.
哦，宝贝，你掉了东西
Oh, honey. You dropped something.
- 不是我的  - 你确定？
- Not mine.  - You sure?
要满十八岁才能玩
You gotta be 18 to play.
看来是某个人不小心把它给洗了
Looks like someone put it through the wash by accident.
昨天的号码，看起来是第二个
Yesterday's drawing. That looks like the second.
也许是哪个废物
Probably a loser.
是啊
Yeah.
我们至少应该看看它有没有中
We should at least see if it hit.
抱歉，先生，我们能不能借一下你的报纸？
Excuse me, sir. Can we borrow your paper for a sec?
- 我们想查一下中奖号码  - 行，没问题
- We're just looking for lottery results.  - Yeah, okay.
都会版，对吧？给你
Metro, isn't it? Here.
- 谢了  - 别客气
- Thanks.  - Yeah.
让我们看一下，在这里，好了，开始了？
Let's see. There it is. Okay, ready?
- 六、十八、三十、四九  - 等等，六、十八，然后呢？
- Six, 18, 30, 49...  - Wait. Six, 18, what?
抱歉，三十、四九、六十
Sorry. Thirty, 49, 60.
- 差了一号  - 哦，开玩笑吧
- Missed by one.  - Oh, you're joking!
- 我生活的写照  - 我也是
- Story of my life.  - Mine too.
- 中了吗？ - 五中四，你能相信吗？
- Any luck?  - Four out of five. Can you believe that?
五中四？那就有五分之四的奖金
Four out of five? Four out of five pays.
- 有吗？ - 当然，对啊
- It does?  - Sure, yeah.
打背面的电话号码问问看
Call the number on the back of the ticket.
谢谢
Well, thanks!
- 这样，谢谢你，非常感谢  - 他们怎么说？
- Well, thank you. Thank you very much.  - What did they say?
我们中了六百块
We won $600!
- 天了噜！ - 圣母！六百块！
- Holy shit!  - Holy moly! Six hundred dollars!
中奖二人组
Couple of winners.
那女人说我们只要拿去核实，他们就会把支票寄过来
The woman said we just take it down for verification, and they'll mail me a check.
我们应该给你妈妈打电话，我们一起去领奖
We should call your mom and we can all go down together.
- 没关系啦，我该回家了  - 不，不，不
- It's okay, I'm supposed to be home.  - No, no, no.
我们五五分账
We're in this 50-50.
好女孩
Good girl.
避开了摄像头
Watch the cameras.
就是这样
That's it.
三百块
Three hundred dollars.
不要在投币机里一次花光，回家后把它藏好
Don't spend it all at the coin-op. Hide it when you get home.
- 我还可以吗？ - 你做得…
- Did I do good?  - You did...
你做得非常好，非常，非常，非常好
You did very good. Very, very, very good.
看吧？老妈错了，我不只遗传到你的手肘
See? Mom was wrong. I didn't just get your elbows.
- 嗯，最后一件事  - 是什么？
- Well, there's one last thing.  - What?
- 我要你把钱还给她  - 什么？
- I want you to give her the money back.  - What?
我是说我会教你怎么骗人，但我可没说我会让你玩真的
I told you I'd teach you a con, I didn't say I'd let you get away with it.
那我要怎么说啊？
What am I supposed to say?
从你刚才的表演看来，我确信你会想出办法的
Judging by that last performance, I'm sure you'll think of something.
这实在太…
This is so...
安吉拉，如果我让你得逞，我就不是个负责任的父亲，去吧
Angela, I would not be a responsible father if I let you get away with this. Let's go!
我说，这很怪，两周前，这不过是段陈年往事
I mean, it's strange. Two weeks ago, this was ancient history.
现在，突然间…
Now, all of a sudden...
我有了个女儿！
...I have a daughter!
而我并没有被吓坏，这是好事，对吧？
And I'm not scared shitless. That's good, isn't it?
- 你无论如何感受都可以，罗伊  - 没错
- It's however you feel about it, Roy.  - Yeah.
是的，这太棒了
Yes, it's wonderful.
别太照字面意思理解，但你关上门很长时间了
Don't take this too literally, but you've been closing doors for a long time.
这是好事，见到你开始打开一点
It's good to see you start opening some again.
怎么了？
What?
我带着安吉拉跟我过周末，卖一样东西
I took Angela along with me over the weekend, selling a piece.
而我的工作有时候…
And sometimes in my business...
你不得不给某样东西定个价，而它一文不值
...you have to create a value for something which really isn't there.
有些人说这叫推销，但别的人则叫它…
Some people call it sales, but other people call it...
- 骗人  - 没错，这有点…
- Lying.  - Right. Which is a little...
我当时不确定安吉拉会如何应对，但她心领神会
I wasn't sure how Angela would go for it, but she took right to it.
如鱼得水，她心领神会，她甚至还帮了忙
Like a duck to water. She took right to it. She even helped out.
你知道，这个十四岁的女孩
You know, this 14-year-old girl...
和我一起操纵那些人
...working these people with me.
操纵他们，医生
Working them, doc.
你后悔了吗？向她暴露这些？让她看见你的这一面？
Do you regret it? Exposing her to that? Her seeing that side of you?
那个嘛，你知道，这有点…这让我觉得…我有点…
Well, you know, it was a little...It made me feel... I was a little...
我真的喜欢这样
I really liked it.
我真的喜欢，那是我俩度过的最好时光
I really did. It was the best time we've had together.
好
Right.
- 了不起的杯子把戏  - 你喜欢吗？
- Fabulous cup trick.  - You like that?
他要带钱飞到开曼群岛去，害怕自己会被抢
He wants to fly the money to the Caymans. Afraid he might get robbed.
像是有人会抢他一样，他什么时候的航班？
As if somebody would do that. When's his flight?
星期五，你怎么想的？
Friday. What do you think?
关于什么？这帽子吗？
About what? The hat?
[德怀特·尤卡姆：乡村歌手]
帽子边有点德怀特·尤卡姆，你说呢？
It's a little Dwight Yoakam around the edges. Is this what you say?
[德怀特·尤卡姆：乡村歌手]
- 你在引人注意  - 对，但小妞们买账
- You're calling attention to yourself.  - Yeah, but the chicks dig it.
- 你在引人注意  - 小妞们买账
- You're calling attention to yourself.  - Chicks dig it.
那么你想在哪呢？
So where do you think?
你打算在哪里下手？
Where do you want to do it?
那里
There.
我在这里，他坐那里
I'm here. He sits there.
背对吧台
Back to the bar.
背对吧台，这很重要
Back to the bar. It's important.
否则，我们就吹了
Otherwise, we blow it off.
好
Okay.
- 谁来干呢？ - 厄尼
- Who's it going to be?  - Ernie.
游民厄尼？
Hobo Ernie?
对，流浪汉厄尼
Yeah, homeless Ernie.
他有点…他有点夸张，不是吗？
He's a little...he's a little over the top, isn't he?
就五十块钱，你知道，便宜到顶了
For 50 bucks, you know, it's a hell of a bargain.
好吧好吧
Okay, okay.
- 现在只有一个问题  - 什么？
- There's only one problem.  - What?
我想我爱上你了
I think I'm in love with you.
- 我们要发财了  - 别这样
- We're gonna be rich.  - Do not do that.
真让人尴尬，快停下
That's embarrassing. Just stop.
- 让你兴奋了吗？ - 不，没让我兴奋，停下
- Does it turn you on?  - No, it does not turn me on. Stop.
你能…？
Can you...?
拿去
Here you go.
- 你那个可爱的小女孩呢？ - 她回她妈家去了
- Where's that cute little girl of yours?  - She went home to her mom's.
暑期班
Summer school.
她很可爱
She's a cute one.
她不在一定很寂寞
Must be lonesome without her.
- 明天见  - 好
- See you tomorrow.  - Okay.
- 你是凯西，对吗？ - 是的
- It's Kathy, right?  - Yeah.
- 我叫罗伊  - 嗨，罗伊
- I'm Roy.  - Hi, Roy.
- 你好吗？ - 我很好
- How are you?  - I'm doing all right.
嗨，老爸，是我，我只是想打声招呼
Hi, Dad, it's me. I just wanted to say hi.
暑期辅导有些烂，所以我星期三中午出来
Summer school sort of sucks. Okay, so I get out at noon on Wednesday.
愿意的话我在门口跟你见面，好了，拜拜
I'll meet you out in front if you want. Okay. Bye.
嗨，老爸，是我，我只是想打声招呼
Hi, Dad, it's me. I just wanted to say hi.
- 变态佬  - 上车
- Pervert.  - Get in the car.
你今天想做什么，小女孩？
What would you like to do today, little girl?
- 妈要我在晚餐前回家  - 你晚饭前能回家
- Mom wants me home by dinner.  - You'll be back by dinner.
你想做什么？
What would you like to do?
怎样？
What?
- 我赢定了  - 哦，是吗？
- I own you.  - Oh, yeah?
咱们得走着瞧
We'll just have to see about that.
让我露两手，在台湾学到的给你瞧瞧
Let me show you a little something I learned in Taiwan.
- 怎样？ - 老爸
- What?  - Dad...
关于这游戏你要了解的第一件事是：
...the first thing you need to understand about this game is...
你出手十次有九次是洗沟
...is 90 percent of it is knocking down at least one pin.
哦，是那样吗？是那样吗？
Oh, is that right? Is that right?
不是吧！
Not now!
- 你要我帮你打吗？ - 好啊，我只要几分钟
- You want me to bowl for you?  - Yeah, I'll just be a couple of minutes.
- 你没问题吧？ - 没事
- You'll be all right?  - Yeah.
好
All right.
最好是很重要的事情，我跟女儿在一起呢
This better be pretty important. I'm with my daughter
- 坏消息，他改期了  - 什么？
- It's bad news. He bumped it up.  - What?
- 他改期了，我们得今天动手  - 我以为是星期五
- He bumped it up. We gotta do it today.  - I thought it was Friday.
我也以为是星期五，可是他改了
I thought it was Friday too, but he changed it.
- 我们现在就得动手  - 跟他讲啊
- We gotta do it now.  - Tell him!
我要跟他讲什么，罗伊？我们不能延期
What am I gonna tell him, Roy? We can't postpone it.
他要去开曼群岛一个月，我们必须马上动手，否则就失败了
He's leaving for the Caymans for a month. We've gotta do it now. Or we're gonna loss it.
看，没时间了，我得去拿钱，我得换装，我得找厄尼…
Look, there's no time. I gotta get the money, I gotta get changed, I gotta get Ernie...
我知道，我知道，可我们没有选择
I know, I know. But we got no choice.
他几点的班机？
What time is his flight?
罗伊
Roy.
- 罗伊？ - 该死
- Roy?  - Shit.
轮到你了
Your turn.
对不起，我得送你回家了
I'm sorry, I gotta take you home.
不行，我不行，来不及了，我都不能送你回家
I can't. I just can't. I can't do this. There's no time. I can't even take you home.
- 你要我自己去搭公车吗？ - 不不，该死！
- Do you want me to take the bus?  - No, no. Shit!
是工作吗？
Is it a job?
我帮得上忙吗？
Can I help?
上车
Get in.
我以为你说过，你把钱存在那只狗里面
I thought you said that kept your money in the dog.
那只是我的存钱罐，好了，我要你在这里等着
That's just my piggy bank. All right, I want you to wait here.
- 要开保险箱，拜托  - 没问题
- Hi, safety deposit box, please.  - Of course.
我要开三六六号的保险箱
I'd like to access safety deposit box 366.
签名还有密码，请
Signature and pass code, please.
- 我为什么不能看？ - 因为这是秘密
- Why can't I see?  - Because it's secret.
那她为什么就可以？
Then why does she get to?
我能给我的账户增加一个访问签名吗？
Can I add an access signature to my account, please?
当然
Certainly.
- 在这里和这里签名  - 签吧
- Sign here and here.  - Do it.
现在，不管是什么我都可以拿了吗？
Now can I get into the whatever-it-is?
不行，你没有密码
No, you don't have the pass code.
- 那我什么时候会有？ - 你知道，等我死了
- When do I get that?  - You know, when I'm dead.
你在这里等着
You wait here.
我认真的
I mean it.
- 小间？ - 不，不要小间
- Booth?  - No! No! No booth!
- 那么里面有多少钱？ - 我说过了
- So how much is in there?  - I told you.
不，那里面！
No, in there!
三十万？
Three hundred thousand?
五十万？
Five hundred thousand?
一百万？
A million?
哦，我的天啊！你怎么会有这么多钱？
Oh, my God! How did you get that money?
我干这行已经很久了
I've been doing this a long time.
你为什么不？你为什么不住到夏威夷去？
Why aren't you...? Why don't you go live in Hawaii?
- 你为什么不把夏威夷买下来？ - 我跟你说过，我不喜欢户外
- Why don't you go buy Hawaii?  - I told you. I don't like the outdoors.
好，你知道怎么做，对吧？离我们远远的
Okay, you know what to do, right? Keep real far away from us.
- 出了任何事，你就离开那里  - 好
- Anything goes off, you get out of there.  - Yeah.
把结婚金戒指递给我，宝贝
Hand me a gold wedding ring, sweetheart.
谢谢，它仍然让我显老？
Thank you. These still make me look old?
又老又有钱
Old and rich.
好了，你记得暗号，对吧？
Okay, you remember your cue, right?
- 这就是暗号，然后你就来  - 我知道
- That's your cue. Then you enter.  - I know.
好，咱们干吧
Okay, let's do this.
预防万一，收下它，好吧？
And just in case, take this, will you?
别再紧张我了，我还什么都还没做呢
Stop worrying about me. I'm barely even doing anything.
我跟她一起出去，但后来我却焦头烂额
I went out with her, but afterwards I was pretty toasted.
- 她有姐妹吗？ - 我不知道
- Does she have any sisters?  - I don't know.
- 亚顿，你还好吗？ - 我的背，我昨晚扭伤了
- Arden, you okay?  - It's my back. I strained it last night.
- 哦，老兄，我跟你说过，你得练瑜珈  - 我当时是在练瑜珈
- Oh, man. I told you, you gotta do yoga.  - I was doing yoga.
你介意我坐这里吗？椅背会让我舒服点
Do you mind if I sit there? The high back helps.
- 完全不  - 谢了
- Not at all.  - Thank you.
哦，天啊
Oh, Lord.
- 你们两个好吗？ - 好极了，谁先来？
- How are both of you?  - Fabulous. So who goes first?
我猜是女士优先，女王先于本·富兰克林
I suppose ladies do. The queen before Ben Franklin.
- 这是八万？ - 没错
- That's 80,000?  - Yeah.
看着比我想像中少很多
Looks like a lot less than I thought.
总是这样，总是这样
It always does. It always does.
抱歉，我得查点一下
Sorry. I had to check.
只要你不介意
As long as you don't mind.
不不，还信不过你吗？
No, no. Do your worst.
你数过了？
It's been counted?
先生们，看来我们成交了
Gentlemen, looks like we have a trade.
- 天佑美国  - 我热爱的土地
- God bless America.  - Land that I love.
好好享受开曼岛，别晒太多太阳
Enjoy the Caymans, and don't get too much sun.
得了，我二十一岁了！我的身分证在行李里
Come on, I'm 21! My ID is in my luggage!
我的飞机半小时后才起飞，给我…
My plane doesn't leave for 30 minutes, give me...
别碰我！你敢碰我，我就把这个地方的所有杯子都砸烂
Don't touch me! You touch me, I'll break every glass in this place!
嘿，机场酒保！
Hey, airport bartender!
希望她不是我一个航班的
Hope she's not on my flight.
说到这，时间差不多了
Speaking of which, it's about that time.
那么，谁先走？
So who goes first?
你先，你站起来把新皮箱一起带走
You do. You just get up and take your new briefcase with you.
我走的时候，把我的新运动包带走
When I leave, I'll take my new gym bag.
- 简单就是安全  - 简单就是安全
- Simple is safe.  - Simple is safe.
各位
Guys.
- 一路平安  - 谢了
- Have a safe flight.  - Thank you.
- 保重，恰克  - 有机会再合作
- Take care, Chuck!  - Let's do it again sometime.
一言为定
You have my word on that.
- 跟他去，送他去登机  - 跟他走什么？
- Go with him. Walk him to the plane.  - Walk him to the what?
- 送他去登机！ - 他们不会让你过安检的
- Walk him to the plane!  - They won't let you to the security check.
那就送他到安检那里，快点，快去！
Then walk him to the security check. Now. Go. Now!
你看见吧台那个化了妆的老娘们了吗？
Did you see that old chick at the bar with the makeup?
- 对，我看见了  - 我摔杯子时，差点把她给吓死了
- Yeah, I saw her.  - She almost died ...when I threw that glass....
- 怎么样了？你拿下他了？ - 对
- So, what happened? You take him?  - Yeah.
整八万？
The whole 80?
我老爸妙手空空
My dad's a smooth operator!
爸，我想过了，我们呢该把钱还回去，我会觉得好点
Dad, I thought about it. We should give the money back. I'd feel better.
开玩笑的
Just kidding.
- 我可以分一份吗？ - 去跟弗兰克分
- Do I get a cut?  - Ask Frank for his.
老爸
Dad! Dad!
下车！你这个下流的骗子！出来！
Get out of the car, you lousy, two-bit con! Get out!
- 给我下车  - 你在干嘛啊？
- Get out of the car!  - What are you doing?
还我的钱来！还我的钱来！
Give me my money! Give me my money!
- 你这个卑鄙的小人  - 把车窗摇起来
- You stinking little runt!  - Roll up the window!
还我的钱来，你这浑蛋！卑鄙…小…
Give me my money, you bitch! Stinking, little...
- 趴下来  - 把钱还给我
- Get down!  - Give me my money!
摇起车窗！
Roll up the window!
你这坨屎！
You piece of shit!
该死的！
Goddamn it!
在这种情况下，保持冷静非常重要
In this situation, it's very important to remain calm.
对不起
I'm so sorry.
- 哪一边？哪一边？ - 中间那个！中间那个
- Which one? Which one?  - The middle one! The middle one.
这个也行
Or this one.
那个，那个
That one! That one!
快点，快点，快点！
Come on, come on! Come on!
- 行了  - 可以给我收据吗？
- Here you go.  - Can I get a receipt?
- 好，可以给你一张  - 快点
- I can get you one.  - Let's go!
我买个汉堡也要收据
I want a hamburger I'll take a receipt...
你连吃个汉堡都要收据？
You saved a receipt for a hamburger?
快点
Come on!
- 我能理解，先生  - 深呼吸，深呼吸
- I understand that, sir.  - Just breathe. Breathe.
可以节税，祝你愉快，谢谢
Save that tax. Have a great day. Thank you.
不用找了，好吗？
Keep the change, okay?
- 不，先生，我们不允许收小费  - 这是一点心意
- No, sir. We're not allowed to accept gratuity.  - It's kindness.
谢谢好意，可是我们不准收，请收下找零
Thanks for being kind, but we're not allowed. Please, take the change.
那就快点
Let's go, come on!
- 五、六、七、八  - 快点，他追来了
- Five, 6, 7, 8...  - Hurry, he's coming!
- 九、十、十一、十二  - 他追来了
- ...9, 10, 11, 12...  - He's coming!
- 你失心疯了？ - 先生！不好意思！
- Are you out of your mind?  - Sir! Excuse me!
你待在车里
You stay in the car.
怎么怎么，怎么了？
What what what? What's wrong?
待在车里
Stay in the car!
嗨，小可爱
Hi, cutie-pie.
- 你从哪里弄来…？ - 你做了什么？
- Where did you get the...?  - What did you do?
我说了…
I told you...
我说要送他去登机！你有送他去登机吗？
I said walk him to the plane! Did you walk him to the plane?
我说过，安检，没机票到不了登机口
I told you, the security. You can't get to the gate without a ticket!
那你亲眼看见他过安检了吗？
Did you see him go through security...?
我女儿今天就在现场！
My daughter was there today!
嘿，又不是我把她拉进来的
Hey, hey, I'm not the one who pimped her...
什么，什么？
What? What?
我说又不是我让她淌这趟浑水的
I said I'm not the one who pimped her into the fucking grift!
别跟我说是我给她带来危险，是她给我们带来危险！
And don't tell me I'm the one who put her at risk. She put us at risk!
- 怎么说？ - 要是他去找警察呢，老兄？
- How?  - What if he goes to the cops, man?
- 他不会，他们从不会  - 要是他会呢？
- He won't. They never do.  - What if he does?
那他就得解释，带着一个装八万块钱的公事包干嘛
He'd have to explain what he's doing with a briefcase ...with $80,000 cash in it...
还有去开曼的机票，明白？
...and a ticket to the Caymans, okay?
我们没有案底，我们是安全的
We're not on the books. We're safe.
我知道我们是，那她呢？
I know we are. What about her?
- 安吉拉从来没被逮过  - 你并不知道，你并不知道
Angela's never been arrested, all right?  You don't know that. You don't know that.
关掉
Turn it off.
好了，告诉他，安吉拉
All right, tell him, Angela.
咱们说清楚，告诉他你没有前科
Let's get this over with. Tell him you're clean.
你从来没被逮过，对吗？
You've never been arrested, have you?
太赞了，太棒了
That's terrific. That's great.
真是漂亮
That's beautiful.
弗兰克
Frank
钱在这里，打电话给我
Here's the money. Give me a call.
耶稣基督
Jesus Christ.
十四岁，你十四岁！你怎么有时间被捕呢？
You're 14! When did you have time to get arrested?
有一次我买口香糖忘记付钱了，就这
I forgot to pay for a pack of gum once. That's it.
哦，那他们就为了一包口香糖报警？
So they called the cops on you over a pack of gum?
还有别的事
And some other stuff.
我可能和保安起了冲突…
I might have put up a fuss when security...
安吉拉
Angela!
那个警卫骚扰我
The guard was groping me.
他抓着我的胸部，我还能怎么办？
He was grabbing at my chest. What was I supposed to do?
- 多久以前的事？ - 去年
- How long ago?  - Last year.
他们给你照相了？印指模了？
They photographed you? They printed you?
把脚移开
Move your leg.
你知道吗，我整个八月都有空，我本来想我可以去找你
You know, I have all of August off. I was thinking I could come visit you.
我们还可以去旅行
We could take a trip, even.
到了九月，是学校的父亲参观日，有些无聊，不过…
In September is fathers' visiting day at school. It's kind of lame, but...
嗯，接下来的几个月我都不在
Yeah, well, I'll be gone for the next couple of months.
弗兰克和我得出城去工作，所以
Frank and I have some out-of-town work, so...
- 那你觉得什么时候能回来？ - 我不知道，实际上
- When do you think you'll be back?  - I don't know, actually.
- 或许等你回来后…  - 好了，听好
- Maybe when you get back...  - Okay, look.
你碍着我们了，懂吗？
You're getting in the way, okay?
你知道，弗兰克和我是搭档，而他说你得走路
You know, Frank and I are partners, and he says you're gone.
那你就得走路
So you're gone.
我以为或许能行得通，可是不行，不行
I thought maybe it could work out, but it can't. It doesn't.
- 快点  - 我不舒服
- Come on.  - I feel sick.
快点下车，快点，走吧
Just get out of the car. Let's go. Come on. Go!
- 我不要走  - 走
- I don't want to go.  - Go!
安吉拉，快走，下车，快点
Angela, move. Get out of the car. Come on.
你妈已经在等你了，快点
Your mother's gonna be waiting for you. Let's go.
走
Go!
也不要再打电话给我，懂吗？不准
And don't ever call me again, okay? Don't.
那是什么？
What's that?
我在机场买给你的
I got it for you at the airport.
我付了钱的
I paid for it.
- 你当初为什么要打电话来？ - 安吉拉，我很抱歉
- Why did you even call me?  - Okay, Angila, I'm sorry.
- 为什么？ - 安吉，我很抱歉，我很抱歉
- Why did you?  - Angie, I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
来吧，回车上来，对不起，行吗？
Come on. Come on back in the car. Come on. I'm sorry, okay?
对不起
I'm sorry.
你不是坏人，你知道，只是你也不算很好
You're not a bad guy, you're just not a very good one.
哈啰？
Hello.
嘿，罗伊，接电话
Hey, Roy, pick it up.
接电话
Pick it up.
- 哈罗？ - 你不要紧吧？
- Hello.  - You all right?
- 没事，有什么事？ - 你饿吗？
- Yeah, what's it look like?  - You hungry?
不
No.
要不要碰个面？我们还有恰克的钱要分？
Want to meet? We still got Chuck's money to split.
几点了？
What time is it?
快三点了
It's almost 3.
- 吃药了没？ - 可不可以等我一下？
- Taking your pills?  - Can you hold on a second?
俾格米土著
Pygmies!
罗伊？
Roy?
- 医学中心  - 麻烦请接克莱恩医生
- Medical Group.  - Yes, Dr. Klein, please.
抱歉，他不在，威利医生有空，你愿意我帮你接他吗？
I'm sorry. He's unavailable. Dr. Wiley is on call if you'd like me to page him.
那很好，不过，我必须跟克莱恩谈
That's very good, but actually, I gotta talk to Klein.
有什么办法可以联络上他吗？
Is there a way I can get ahold of him?
很抱歉，克莱恩医生这个周末都不在
I'm sorry, Doc. Klein is gone for the weekend.
他去哪里了？
Where did he go?
好了，听我说，我需要那个新药
Okay, look, look. Listen, I need a new thing of pills.
那你现在在他的办公室吗？
Well, actually, are you at his office now?
- 很抱歉，先生，办公室关了  - 该死
- I'm sorry, sir. The office is closed.  - Shit!
- 我的电话快没电了  - 是的，先生
- Sorry, my phone is dying.  - Yes, sir.
如果是医疗紧急事故，请与当地的医院联络或是打九一一
If this is a medical emergency, contact your local hospital or call 911.
救救我，你能不能行行好，救我救我救我
Help me! Is there a way you can help me help you help me...
让我进去他的办公室？
...so that I can get in his office?
[迪索多药房]
别忘了吃的时候要多喝点水
Don't forget to drink plenty of water with that.
- 对不起，嗨  - 我马上就好，先生
- Excuse me, hi.  - I'll be right with you, sir.
我需要补充点药，我没有处方笺
I need a refill. I don't have a prescription...
- 先生，请排队等候  - 我知道，可是这很紧急
- Sir, please wait your turn.  - I know, but this is an emergency.
老兄，有没有听说过排队？
Buddy, ever heard of a line?
有没有被拉到路边，然后被打到尿血过？
Ever been dragged to the sidewalk and beaten until you pissed blood?
听我说，我真的需要，谢谢
Listen, I'm sorry, I really need... Thank you.
谢谢
Thank you.
- 我要拿药  - 你有处方笺吗？
- I need a refill of this.  - Do you have a prescription?
没有，可是我的医生，精神科医生，给我这些，是样品…
No, but my doctor, my shrink, gave me these, and they're samples of...
该死！我记不得了，哦，普利发还是什么的
Dam it! I can't remember... Prefex something.
我很抱歉，先生，没有处方笺，我什么也不能做
I'm sorry, sir. Without a prescription, there's nothing I can do.
可是我有包装，所以我显然是被允许拿药的
But I have the packet, so I'm clearly allowed to have them.
我只需要四、五颗，让我撑过这个周末
I need four or five of them to cover me for the weekend.
- 让我看看  - 谢谢
- Let me see it.  - Thank you.
我很抱歉，先生
And I am sorry, sir.
- 这些是营养补充剂  - 什么？
- These are supplements.  - What?
- 这里面是营养补充剂，先生  - 不，不，不
- This packet contains supplements, sir.  - No, no, no.
是医生给我的，它们是普利发
My doctor gave those to me. They're Prefex.
- 它们是营养补充剂，先生  - 胡说，老兄！普利发
- They're supplements, sir  - Bullshit, man! Prefex.
- 萨普利芬  - 普利发
- Supplifem.  - Prefex!
- 在第四排，先生  - 普利发
- Aisle four, sir.  - Prefex!
你叫警卫了吗？
Did you call security?
[萨普利芬 大豆蛋白 更年期补充剂]
你给我的就是这个？
Did you give me this?
- 是的  - 为什么？
- Yes.  - Why?
- 因为你没必要吃药  - 看看我，我糟透了
- Because you don't need medication.  - Look at me, I'm a mess.
同意，不过你上星期还好，你也…
Agreed. But you weren't a mess last week, and you weren't on...
不需要普利发
...Prefexall then either.
我有新消息，你的神经症状没什么
I have news for you. Your neurosis is small-time.
没什么？你是哪门子的？你他妈的庸医！
Small-time? What are you a...? You fucking quack!
你的良心就另当别论了
Your conscience is another story.
我问你个问题，如果要转行，你会干什么？
Let me ask a question. What would you do if you had to change careers?
什么，要是我不当古董经纪？
What, if I wasn't an antiques broker?
要是你不当罪犯
If you weren't a criminal.
我放过脚的是一只十八世纪安妮王后的脚凳，罗伊
That's an 18th century Queen Anne footstool I've had my feet on, Roy.
曾经有电脑工程师跟我说过它多么好
I've had computer programmers tell me what a nice piece it is.
我才不是什么罪犯
I'm not a criminal.
我是行骗艺术家
I'm a con artist.
- 区别是？ - 钱是他们给我的
- The difference being?  - They give me their money.
真是合理的说法，罗伊
That's a nice rationalization, Roy
我搞的人都是出于贪心和缺点才让我得手
I never took anybody who didn't let me out of greed or weakness.
而且我从不
And I never...
使用暴力
...used violence.
你是说你给这一行树立了榜样？
Would you say then you set an example in your trade?
当之无愧
You bet I do.
可是你现在得给另一个人树立榜样
But now you have to set an example for someone else.
她还好吗？
How is she?
安吉拉
Angela.
她很好
She's fine.
她回她妈那儿了
She went back to her mom's.
你跟她谈过吗？
Have you spoken to her?
为什么不？
Why not?
我们一定要讨论这件事吗？
Do we have to talk about this?
你们为什么不谈谈？
Why haven't you spoken?
因为…
Because...
她恨我
she hates me.
你怎么认为她恨你呢？
Why do you think she hates you?
因为
Because...
因为我搞砸了
Because I screwed it up.
哦，老天，我失去了我的小姑娘了
Oh, God. I lost my little girl.
我失去我的小姑娘
I lost my little girl.
我很高兴…
I'm happy to...
我去见过一个律师
I went to see a lawyer.
他的专业是监护权
He specializes in custody suits.
那一类事情
That sort of thing.
比如父母一方想要孩子的共同监护权
Like when one parent wants to get joint custody of the child.
你必须做一些事情
There are things you have to do...
提出书面文件
...file some paperwork...
验血，面对一个法官
...blood tests, go before a judge.
一开始只有周末和一些假日见面
It would only be for weekends and some holidays to start.
不过我必须得做许多改变
But I'd have to make a lot of changes.
其中之一，我的谋生手段必须停手
For one thing, I'd have to stop doing what I do for a living.
宝贝，对不起，我应该先问你的
Honey, I'm sorry. I should have asked you first.
你愿意试试看吗？
Will you try? Please?
是的，我会试试看
Yes, I'll try, honey.
我会的
I'll try.
从什么时候？
When?
就现在
As of now.
你得做你必须做的
You gotta do what you gotta do.
遗憾失去了你
I'm sorry to lose you.
你不要那四万块？
You don't want the 40 G's?
留着吧，就当成是临别礼物
Keep it. Consider it a parting gift.
那我们应该多多分手
We should part more often.
我说过我爱你吗？
Did I tell you I love you?
是，我也爱你
Yeah, I love you back.
- 遵守  - 遵守
- Comply  - Comply
总有一天，我要把你灌醉
One of these days, I'm gonna get you drunk.
我觉得这事我应该告诉你妈妈，让她知道我的打算
You know I think I should tell your mom about this. Let her know what I'm doing.
- 你的葬礼  - 我知道
- Your funeral.  - I know.
不过，我想她应该从我这里听到
But I think she should hear it from me.
你觉得呢？
What do you think?
没错
Yeah.
那好
Okay.
- 我好期待  - 我们可以养只狗
- I'm excited about this.  - We could get a dog.
- 德国牧羊犬或是拉不拉多  - 狗不是很脏吗？
- Either a German shepherd or a Lab.  - They're messy, aren't they?
我们可以训练它啊
We could train it.
- 取名为弗兰克  - 好名字
- Name it Frank.  - That's a good name.
小姐（西班牙语）
Senorita
不错
That's nice.
小姐（西班牙语）
Senorita
- 给你，小姐  - 谢谢
- For you, senorita.  - Thank you.
我们去跳舞
Let's dance.
什么意思？“我家就是你家”？
What is it, "my house is your house"?
弗兰克
Frank!
退后
Get back.
哈啰？罗伊
Hello, Roy.
- 嗨，小可爱  - 回你房间等着，宝贝
- Hiya, sunshine.  - Go wait in your room, honey.
她留下，她跟你们一样牵涉
Let her stay. She's in this as much as you are.
安吉拉，对吧？
It's Angela, right?
你的档案照可比不上你
Your mug shot doesn't do you justice.
想坐下吗？
You wanna sit down?
- 如果你敢靠近她  - 别装硬汉，罗伊，我可是在你家
- If you come anywhere near her...  - Don't play tough. I'm in your home.
罗伊，对不起，老兄
Roy, I'm sorry, man.
闭嘴
Shut up!
你怎么找到我的？
How did you find me?
我没有
I didn't.
我找到了她，真真切切
I found her in black and white.
机场保安摄像头，罗伊，它们正拍到她了
Airport security cameras, Roy, they got a nice look at her.
真是粗心
That was sloppy.
- 候机室并没有摄像头  - 是没有
- There were no cameras in the lounge.  - No.
礼品店里有
There were in the gift shop.
我这一行，在警局里有几个朋友
In my business, it pays to have a few friends on the force.
你的小姑娘在他们的档案里
Your little girl's in their books.
你的前妻并不知道不该给我你的地址
Your ex-wife doesn't know well enough not to give out your home address.
我们只会被所爱的人伤害，呃？
We only hurt the ones we love, huh?
你的脸色苍白得像鬼，罗伊
You look white as a ghost, Roy.
我不想要你昏过去，你得先还债
I don't want you to pass out before you make your first payment.
先办正事，把你从我这儿拿的钱还来
First things first, let's have the money you took from me.
- 我没有  - 那就先从你有的开始
- I don't have it.  - Well, let's start with what you do have!
- 我有四千块，可能  - 在哪？
- Four thousand, maybe.  - Where?
那只狗
The dog.
站住！
Stop!
让她去拿，你跟我待在一起
Let her get it. You stay here with me.
没事的，宝贝，去吧
It's okay. It's okay, honey, go.
跑，安吉拉，快跑
Run, Angela! Run!
你跑，老爸现在就死！
You run, and Daddy's dead right now!
好，好
Okay, okay.
接下来，你以后赚的钱我都要分一半
Next, I get half of whatever you make from now on.
否则，我就给我的警察朋友打电话
If not, I call those cop friends of mine
你的小姑娘到十八岁就去坐牢吧
your little girl goes to juvy till she's 18.
我退出了，我收手不干了
I'm out. I'm done with this.
你还没收手，罗伊
You're not done, Roy.
你都没沾湿鞋子呢
You haven't even gotten your feet wet.
弗兰克还没收手，对吧，弗兰克？
Frank's not done, are you, Frank?
你收手了，弗兰克？
You done, Frank?
他可没有
He's not done.
安吉拉，不，把枪放下，宝贝
Angela, no. Put the gun down, sweetheart
- 打他  - 安静，弗兰克
- Shoot him.  - Quiet, Frank.
安吉拉，行了，安吉拉
Angela, okay. Angela. Angela.
把枪放下，宝贝，不要…我来处理
Put it down, sweetheart. Don't... I'll take care of this.
- 我要你走  - 知道怎么用那个吗？
- I want you to go.  - Know how to use that?
- 别越弄越糟  - 开枪打他
- Don't make it worse!  - Shoot him!
该死，开枪打他！
Goddamn it, shoot him!
好了，好了
Okay, okay.
哦，不会吧，哦，天啊
Oh, no. Oh, no. Oh, God.
哦，天啊
Oh, God.
- 哦，天啊  - 哦，该死，罗伊
- Oh, God!  - Oh, shit, Roy.
他撑不过去的
He ain't gonna make it.
好了，好了，好了
Okay, okay, okay, okay.
你知道七棕榈汽车旅馆在哪吗？
You know where the Seven Palms Motel is?
- 在十五号公路上  - 好，去那开个房间
- It's out at the 15.  - Okay, get a room there.
要一楼的，万一你要从后门出去，在那里等我
Ground floor, if you have to go out the back. Wait there for me.
要是你没来呢？
What if you don't show?
就带她去她妈妈那里，然后往南开永远别回来
Take her to her mother's, and drive south and never come back.
那你要干什么呢？
What are you gonna do?
我要送他去医院
I'm gonna take him to the hospital.
安吉拉，宝贝
Angela, sweetheart.
听我说，弗兰克会带你离开这里，好吗？
Listen to me. Frank will get you out of here, all right?
他会带你离开这里，我过一两天就去找你
He's gonna get you out of here, and I will see you in a day or two.
- 不会有事的，我保证  - 爸，我只是想
- Everything will be all right, I promise.  - Dad, I was just trying to...
我知道，我知道，听着，我知道
I know, I know. Listen to me. Listen, I know, I know.
你没有开枪，好吗？
You didn't shoot him, all right?
明白吗？是我开枪的，是我
Do you understand? I shot him. I did.
- 是不是这样，弗兰克？ - 没错，罗伊
- Isn't that right, Frank?  - Right, Roy.
好了，你好好等着就行，宝贝
All right, so you just sit tight, honey.
而且我想要你知道，我很抱歉
And I want you to know that I'm sorry.
对不起让你失望了
I'm sorry I let you down.
好了，弗兰克
Okay, Frank.
- 快走吧  - 好
- Go, okay?  - Okay.
- 我说真的  - 罗伊，对不起，老兄
- I'm serious.  - Roy, I'm sorry. I'm sorry, man.
- 没关系  - 我真的很抱歉
- All right. All right.  - I'm really sorry.
你没事了
You're okay, man.
- 他没事了  - 霍夫曼护士请到小儿科
- He's okay.  - Nurse Hoffman to Pediatrics.
- 霍夫曼护士请至小儿科  - 早安，罗伊，你觉得怎么样？
- Nurse Hoffman to Pediatrics.  - Good morning, Roy. How do you feel?
冷
Cold.
慢慢来，好吗？
Take it slow, will you?
我是比绍普探员，这是赫特探员
I'm Detective Bishop. This is Detective Holt.
医生马上就来了
The doctor will be in in a second.
那晚你被理了个相当不错的发型，罗伊
You were given a pretty close haircut the other night, Roy.
严重脑震荡
Bad concussion.
你还算走运，罗伊，我们希望恰克也走运
You got lucky, Roy. I wish we could say the same for Chuck.
我被捕了吗？
Am I under arrest?
你有权利保持缄默，你所说的一切可能…不拉不拉…
Well, you have the right to remain silent. Anything you say can and may be...
我都听见了
I heard it all.
罗伊，弗兰克在哪里？
Roy, where's Frank?
- 谁？ - 弗兰克·莫瑟，你的搭档
- Who?  - Frank Mercer. Your partner.
我们搜过你家和他家，没有多少是我们不知道的
We've been spending time at your places.- There's not a lot we don't know.
我更喜欢你家，干净
I like your place better. Clean.
他在哪里？
Where is he?
好吧，那这样吧？
Okay, then how about this?
安吉拉在哪？
Where's Angela?
因为她不在切斯特大道四百一十五号
Because she's not at 415 Chester Ave.
她妈妈都快抓狂了
Her mother's near hysterical.
是我开的枪
I shot him.
我开枪打了恰克
I shot Chuck.
你确定吗？
You sure about that?
因为恰克没挺过来，我们发现他趴在你的车道上
Because Chuck didn't make it. We found him facedown in your driveway.
真是倒霉，不过我告诉你，还有更糟糕的
It's not good, but I'm telling you, it could still get a lot worse.
哎哟喂，我们从你的点三八上采到的指纹有些小
Alas, the print we took off your .38 was just a little small.
那么她在哪？
So where is she?
我要见我的医生
I wanna see my doctor.
我们说过，医生马上就来了
Like we said, the doctor will be here in a second.
不，我的精神科医生
No, my doctor, my shrink.
你们让我见他，你们想知道的我都告诉你们
You let me see him, and I'll tell you everything you wanna know.
他电话号码是？
What's his number?
哈罗，罗伊
Hello, Roy.
- 嘿，医生  - 嗨
- Hey, doc.  - Hi.
我们能不能有点私人空间？
Can we have a little privacy?
事情不是这么办的
That's not the way it works.
我不是应该有医患隐私特权什么的吗？
Don't I have doctor-patient privileges, rights, something?
是的，技术上说，他没错
Yeah, technically, he's right.
那样会牵涉到你可能讲出些基于机密信息的证言
That refers to testimony you might give based on confidential information.
没有哪个特权说我必须让你们独处
There's no privilege says I gotta leave you two alone.
或者，如果你想要我知道的信息，就有
Or, there is if you want what I know.
五分钟
Five minutes.
罗伊，出什么事了？他们说…
Roy, what happened? They told...
好了，听着，安吉拉有麻烦了
Okay, listen. Angela is in trouble.
如果我不帮她，她就得坐牢了
If I don't help her, she will go to jail.
拜托你帮我救救她
So please help me help her.
我不能做犯法的事
I can't do anything illegal.
- 带累她你也有份  - 别转移责任，罗伊
- You got her into this too.  - Don't transfer responsibility, Roy.
帮我打个电话就好了，行吗？求求你？
Just make a phone call for me, all right? Please?
好吧
All right.
打电话到贝克尔斯菲的七棕榈汽车旅馆
Check out Seven Palms Motel in Bakersfield.
像是巨型蟋蟀的叫声
It's like a giant cricket.
然后呢？
And then what?
我叫过你把那机器关掉，对吗？
I asked you to turn the machine off, right?
你告诉安吉拉密码，然后叫她写下来
Tell Angela the pass code, and then you tell her to write it down.
- 密码？ - 你出去时他们会搜你的身
- Pass code?  - They'll search you on your way out.
- 对  - 是五四三N七九四二
- Right.  - It's 543N7942.
- 五九…  - 医生
- 59...  - Doc!
哦，对不起
Oh, I'm sorry.
五四三N七九四二，跟我重念一遍，重念
543N7942. Say it back to me. Say it back.
那是五四三N七五四二
So it's 543N7542.
不，是N七九四二
No, N7942.
N，诺曼的“N”，七九四二
N, Norman, 7942.
- 你只要办到这个就行  - 五四三N七九四二
- That's all you have to do.  - 543N7942.
五四三N七九四二
543N7942.
谢谢你，医生
Thank you, doc.
她不会有事的
She's gonna be okay.
安吉拉不会有事的
Angela's gonna be all right.
嘿，哈罗？
Hey, hello?
嘿，你们谁来开一下空调啊？
Hey, can you guys put the air conditioning on?
很热
It's hot.
叫什么来着？比绍普？比绍普！
What is it? Bishop? Bishop!
警探们，你们能不能让这里…
Detectives, can you make it a little...
凉快点？
...cooler in here?
[罗伊的]
亲爱的罗伊，你可能非常沮丧，我不怪你
Dear Roy, you're probably pretty upset. I don 't blame you.
我懂的东西大多是你教的，所以我实在不应该这么对你的
You taught me most of what I know, so I suppose I owe you better than this.
但你总是跟我说如果逮到大机会，我应该抓住它
But you always told me if I ever got a shot at a big score, I should take it.
所以我就这么办了
And that's what I did.
出租车
Taxi!
对不起
Sorry, sorry!
很抱歉打破你的头，还有其它的一切
Sorry about the sap on the head, by the way, and for everything else.
你总说我们这样的人，承受不起对自己所做的事后悔
You always said guys like us can 't afford to have regrets about what we do.
这我来说有点为难，不过我会调整的
That's gonna be a little harder for me, but I'll manage.
哦，不，我告诉她我是精神科医生，我不能说谎，罗伊
Well, no, I told her I'm a psychiatrist. I can 't lie, Roy.
嘿，嘿嘿，老兄
Hey, hey, hey, hey, pal!
如果这话能让你好受点：你是我见过最棒的
If it makes any difference, you're the best I ever saw.
我再也找不到更好的搭档了，现在我也不需要了
I'd never find a better partner, and now I won 't have to.
我爱你，老兄
I love you, man.
弗兰克
Frank.
今天要小间吗，沃勒先生？
Booth today, Mr. Waller?
附注：希望你喜欢这份礼物
P.S. Enjoy the gift.
[爱你，弗兰克]
附注：希望你喜欢这份礼物
P.S. Enjoy the gift.
她说你是个坏人
She said you were a bad guy.
你看起来不像坏人
You don 't seem like a bad guy.
我不觉得你是个坏人
Well, I don 't think you're a bad guy.
罗伊？
Roy?
海瑟
Heather.
她…
She's...
她不在这里，对吗？
She's not here, is she?
- 什么？ - 安吉拉
- What?  - Angela.
谁？什么？
Who? What?
罗伊，你在说什么？
Roy, what are you talking about?
孩子，你当时快生孩子了
The baby. You were gonna have a baby.
你是为这件事来的吗？
That's why you're here?
你当时怀孕了
You were pregnant.
那时候你怀孕了！你怀孕了
You were pregnant! You were. You were pregnant.
我流产了
I lost it.
罗伊，你还好吗？
Roy, you okay?
是，我没事
Yeah, I'm okay.
[一年后]
我失陪一下
Excuse me one second.
- 嘿，老板  - 罗伊，有生意上门了
- Hey, boss.  - Roy, another live one.
好的
All right.
午安
Afternoon.
- 你好吗？ - 有什么我可以效劳的？
- How you doing?  - Can I help you find anything?
对，我想买地毯
Yeah, I need a carpet.
- 要铺在家里的吗？ - 是要铺在秘书的办公室
- For your home?  - For my secretary's office.
不，是要铺在公寓里的
No, it's for my apartment.
- 只有一个房间  - 大地方？
- All one room of it.  - Big place?
- 算是吧  - 那你有中意的颜色吗？
- Oh, yeah.  - All right, well, you have a color in mind?
我有中意的价钱，便宜
I have a price in mind. Cheap.
好，你要求不多，你不知道自己想要什么…
Okay, so you don't need much, you don't know what you want...
只要价钱别太高就好
but no price is too low.
差不多是
That's about me.
你是我的完美顾客，我们到余料堆里找找
You are my perfect customer. Let's dig into the remnants.
等等，我女朋友对我们的需求比我了解一点
Wait, wait, wait. My girlfriend knows a bit better than I do what we need.
嘿，宝贝
Hey, sweetie.
她来了
There she is.
哦，我…
Oh, I...
我觉得我们应该找颜色暗点的，因为有狗
I think we should go with the dark because of the dog.
哦，对，说得没错，我们刚养了只狗
Oh, yeah, yeah, yeah. Fair enough. We just got a dog.
让我猜猜，是拉不拉多犬
Let me guess, a Lab.
德国牧羊犬，不过
German shepherd, but...
我下一个就要猜它
My next guess.
有没有，比如…
There's no, like...
我不知道，狗喜欢的特殊地毯，有吗？
...I don't know, special carpet that dogs like, is there?
有，有，我们叫阿斯特洛夫尼龙
Yeah, yeah. We call it AstroTurf.
来吧，余料在商店的后部
Come on, remnants are in the back of the store.
你们刚刚才住在一起？
You folks just move in together?
对，三星期前
Yeah, three weeks ago.
- 重要的一步  - 我喜欢这个
- Big step.  - I kind of like this one.
对，选得好，颜色深你都注意不到污渍
Yeah, that's a nice choice. So dark you barely notice stains.
你喜欢？
You like it?
多少钱？
How much is it?
牌价是七十五块，不过我可以折百分之二十，只要你付现金
Well, the sticker says 75, but I can knock 20 percent off if you pay cash.
我们的生活安排，我付房租，她买地毯
This is our living arrangement. I pay rent. She buys the carpets.
- 糟糕  - 怎么了？
- Shit.  - What's up?
我想我把钱包留在…
I think I left my wallet...
对，我把钱包留在车子里了
Yeah, I left my wallet in the car.
- 你可以去拿吗？ - 好
- Do you think you could go get it?  - Yeah.
我这就回来
I'll be right back.
谢谢你什么也没说
Thanks for not saying anything.
你在这里做多久了？
How long have you worked here?
一阵子了
A while.
那么，怎么，你正在钓这家伙？
So, what, you working this guy?
不是
No.
不不不，我退休了
No, no. No, I'm retired.
那次是…一次性的
That was a one-time deal.
没开玩笑？你很…
No kidding? You were...
厉害
...good.
我有个好老师
I had a good teacher.
- 老师们  - 我有点惊讶会在这里遇见你
- Teachers.  - I'm kind of surprised to see you here.
我琢磨你早就去了…
I figured you would have moved out to...
说不好，夏威夷？
I don't know, Hawaii.
分钱的时候我有些上当了，你了解弗兰克的
I kind of got screwed on my cut. You know Frank.
常在河边走，哪能不湿鞋，对吗？
You're gonna go swimming, you're gonna get wet, right?
你的发型变了
You changed your hair.
看起来像成年人
Makes you look grown-up.
我是成年人
I am grown-up.
你总是穿成这样出门吗？
You always go out dressed like this?
有时候
Sometimes.
干嘛，你要罚我跪吗？
Why, you gonna ground me?
抱歉
Sorry.
我也很抱歉
I'm sorry too...
如果可以补偿的话
...if it's any consolation.
你生我气吗？
You mad at me?
你并没有拿走
You didn't take it.
是我给你的
I gave it to you.
这种看法有意思
It's a funny way of looking at it.
我现在看事情的角度不同了
Well, I see things differently now.
你喜欢这个人？
So you like this guy?
是的，他很疼我
Yeah, he's sweet to me.
我是在保龄球馆认识他的
I met him at a bowling alley.
我们有过美好时光，对吗？
We had a good time, didn't we?
对，有过
Yeah, we did.
- 谢了，伙计  - 就放这里
- Thanks, buddy.  - Right here.
- 我来把它绑紧  - 很高兴见到你，罗伊
- Let me tie it off.  - It's good to see you, Roy.
我也很高兴见到你
It's good to see you too.
你不想知道我的名字吗？
Don't you wanna know my name?
我知道你的名字
I know your name.
回头见，老爸
I'll see you, Dad.
嗨
Hi.
一共是三十六块五，先生
That'll be 36.50, sir.
歌手｜Frank Sinatra
歌名｜Summer Wind
专辑｜Nothing But The Best
♪ 夏日之风 ♪
♪ The summer wind ♪
♪ 徐徐吹来 ♪
♪ came blowing in ♪
♪ 越洋而来 ♪
♪ from across the sea ♪
♪ 在那里徘徊 ♪
♪ It lingered there ♪
♪ 轻触你的头发 ♪
♪ to touch your hair ♪
♪ 与我漫步 ♪
♪ and walk with me ♪
♪ 整个夏天 ♪
♪ All summer long ♪
♪ 我们唱一支歌 ♪
♪ we sang a song ♪
♪ 然后我们漫步 ♪
♪ and then we strolled ♪
♪ 在那金色沙滩 ♪
♪ that golden sand ♪
♪ 两个爱人 ♪
♪ Two sweethearts ♪
♪ 陪伴夏日之风 ♪
♪ and the summer wind ♪
♪ 如同描画的风筝 ♪
♪ Like painted kites ♪
♪ 那些日日夜夜 ♪
♪ those days and nights ♪
♪ 它们飞过天空 ♪
♪ they went flying by ♪
♪ 世界是新的 ♪
♪ The world was new ♪
♪ 在蓝色伞盖般的天空下 ♪
♪ beneath a blue umbrella sky ♪
翻译修订&时间轴｜goodliuwu
字幕转制｜天外生物
感谢原字幕制作者